I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Has it been two years?
Episode 1
Balsa, the Female Bodyguard
...and swing your plows!
Sow the rice seeds
and make the seedlings sprout!
Nahji, come, come!
Swarm like a black cloud and
fly down from the northern mountains.
It's good to be in Yogo.
I can feel my soul
growing more tranquil.
What is it?
It's not often that you
see a woman warrior.
Are you from Kanbal?
Well, yes. I'm here for
maintenance on my short spear.
Maintenance?
Well, unlike Kanbal, you can
get anything you need in Yogo.
That's assuming, of course,
that you have money.
Perhaps.
But those with money end up
living the same life wherever they go.
Having none, however, means
you can live as those around you do.
And there's really nothing
wrong with that.
You're quite philosophical
for someone so young.
I'm not young any more.
I'll be 30 this year.
Listen, you!
It's a royal family procession!
But I'm not from this country.
I have no obligation whatsoever.
He's going to fall!
There he is...
He's just a child?
What happened back there?
He must've lost
consciousness right away.
He didn't swallow any water.
Step aside!
Commoners such as you must never
look upon one of the royal family!
Do not look at him!
Hurry, send for a carriage and doctor!
Listen! Get rid of that crowd!
I had a feeling it was you, Tanda.
Is something wrong?
For you to come all
the way to Ogi no Shimo...
I gather she hasn't come here yet?
Sorry, Tanda.
But it's been two years now.
I wouldn't be surprised if Balsa
came back any day now.
I hope you're right...
Would you like to come inside, Tanda?
No, I'll visit with you some other time.
I have an order for medicinal herbs,
so I'll be in town for a few days.
If we hear anything about Balsa,
you'll be the first to know.
I hear they read this
would-be hero the riot act!
Can you believe the gall of that guy?
Thank you for your patience.
Sake! Bring us some more sake!
Here you go!
Very well!
Wait!
There is something
we'd like to ask you.
We heard that a warrior
rescued a member...
...of the royal family
from Aoyumi River today.
We are searching for this person.
Rumor has it that this warrior
was a short-spear bearer.
Would you happen to know
anything of this warrior?
Not a thing...
Just as I thought.
Forget we had this conversation!
I can see you don't
want me to just forget it.
I wouldn't if I were you.
With your skills, you'd be killed twice
before your sword was drawn.
Wait!
I realize we have
acted with disrespect.
We are emissaries from the court...
...and have been searching for you
on orders of the second queen.
The second queen?
Hearing that it was a skilled
warrior who saved the prince...
...we assumed it was a man,
and have only been questioning men.
But I am now convinced
that this warrior was, in fact, you.
You have my word
that we will do you no harm!
Please, do us the honor of
accompanying us to Ninomiya Palace.
Not what I had in mind.
I should've had this repaired
as soon as I arrived.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
This is quite a view.
If this palace is so lavish, the mikado's
lifestyle must be beyond belief.
I'd hate to see this feast go to waste.
Then again, why would
they poison me now?
Forgive us for not being more
effusive after inviting you here.
A foreigner such as yourself
might not be aware of this, but...
We commoners are unable
to look directly into the eyes...
...of a member of the royal family.
If we do, we will instantly
be struck blind in both eyes.
Well, that is one of the reasons...
But the second queen is most
grateful to you for saving the prince.
This money is your reward.
The amount is paltry for the life
of a prince, but please accept it.
Also, Her Majesty the
second queen herself...
...has instructed me to ask you
to spend the night here.
No, you have already done
more than enough for me.
Now, now...
Please, do us the honor
of staying the night.
Your belongings have been
taken to your room.
Thank you.
What can I say?
At any rate, what on earth
is this futon made of?
I wonder if the nobility are called
"those who dwell on the clouds"...
...because they sleep on
these huge things every night.
Oh, never mind!
This may be my only chance to
experience what they call "heaven"!
Warrior from another land...
Are you awake?
Yes, I'm awake. Please come in.
I see that you are indeed
as formidable a woman as they say.
You look us in the eye,
and yet you do not fall blind.
Thank you for
rescuing the prince today.
You have my deepest gratitude.
I am unworthy of your kind words.
You have already shown me
hospitality of the highest order.
Any further gestures
are most unnecessary.
I see.
Even so, I expect that you
must find our coming to visit you...
...in the middle of the night
to be most unusual.
Look up, Balsa. Show me your face!
Just as my attendants said,
you have a fearless look in your eye.
You are known by the name
Balsa the Spear-wielder.
They say that there are none
who do not know your name...
...that you have the appearance
of a warrior of distant Kanbal...
...and that your skills have
saved many lives over the years.
Is this wrong?
Your Majesty...
What you have heard are no more than
rumors that embellish my reputation.
I am a bodyguard who protects
others for money, nothing more.
Ah, I see.
Why do you risk your life
to earn money performing such work?
In truth, it is the hope
that I place in your ability...
...that has brought me
here to ask this favor.
I do not care where you flee.
Will you take this child...
...and protect him for the rest of
his life from the mikado's assassins?
From the mikado's assassins?
Today it was an ox cart.
Half a month ago,
he had a narrow escape...
...when a geyser suddenly
erupted at the hot springs.
But why in the world would
the mikado want to kill the prince?
It all began some two months ago.
Night after night, the child began
mumbling strange things in his sleep.
When I had his tutor, a star reader,
observe him as he slept...
...he told me that some unknown
force had possessed the child.
Fortunately, this star reader
is honorable and trustworthy.
We told no one, turning instead
to a magic weaver of the Yakoo.
However, the star reader consulted
not only this magic weaver...
...but the master star reader as well.
I suspect that the mikado
secretly ordered the prince's death...
...upon receiving
the master star reader's counsel.
Merely for that reason?
If word of this gets out
and rumors begin to spread...
...it would irreparably damage
the good name of the mikado.
You! Have you been
disrespectful to my mother?
No, she has not, Chagum.
I have asked her to
safeguard your life.
But wait a moment...
Wait!
Chagum, you must listen to me.
From this moment on, I want you
to follow her wherever she goes...
...and no matter what happens,
you must not die.
You ceased to be a prince the instant
the mikado ordered your death.
Even so, you must not harbor
ill will towards the mikado.
He bears the terrible responsibility
of ruling this country.
Bring it in.
A commoner could not spend all
this in a lifetime, try as she might.
Please give me your word that you
will accept this and protect my child.
Your Majesty, I understand the gist
of your request. However...
This is a most dishonorable
way for you to treat me.
In what way?
For my life to be forfeit as a reward
for having saved the prince's life...
How is that not dishonorable?
No one is suggesting
that you be killed.
Are you certain about that?
If someone of my low social status
were to hear a story such as yours...
...that person would have no choice
but to agree to your request.
And yet once she agreed, her life
would be more or less in jeopardy.
And you are too unfamiliar with
the ways of the world, Your Majesty.
If I ever tried to pay for something
with gems bearing this palace crest...
...our whereabouts would be
discovered at once.
I see. However, this is the only money
that I have at my disposal.
But you are correct.
I cannot allow one who has...
...learned this secret to leave
without consequence.
Balsa! You can either die here or take
a chance at survival with the prince.
Choose one or the other!
For a queen...
...you certainly don't seem to
have many trustworthy men.
Two in the room behind me.
Three in the hallway.
Counting these two, you have
seven in all, which is quite pitiful.
Don't make a move!
For starters, I'll take the treasure.
You two!
Fill this with as much as will fit!
Your Majesty, earlier you asked
why it is that I work as a bodyguard.
In the past, I was forced to take
the lives of eight dear people.
And so, to appease the souls
of those eight people...
...I am working as a bodyguard until
I've saved an equal number of lives.
Eight people's souls?
I will protect the prince.
Go with her, Chagum.
Trust her as I do.
Come!
Mother!
No, I don't want to go! Mother!
You! If you want the prince
to escape to safety...
...start by setting a fire
in his bedchamber!
And then take us to the
palace's secret escape route!
Hand me the bag.
Take care, Your Majesty.
Balsa!
If you include my son's life,
how many lives will you have saved?
Your Majesty, his life will be the eighth.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Balsa goes into hiding in the Yogo city.
But she and Chagum
are given no time to rest.
Next time, "Hunters, Hunted."
Episode 2
Hunters, Hunted
The mikado's shadow servants...
...are about to be unleashed.