I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
This way! Start chopping
the walls down here!
We'll make our firebreak here
to keep the fire from spreading!
Hey, that's a ruisha.
Take good care of that.
The person you were as
Prince Chagum died tonight.
From now on, you're going
to live as just Chagum.
Once I accept a job,
I see it through no matter what.
I'm not going to let you die.
That's what I was hired to do.
I know it will be difficult for you,
but bear with it and survive.
If you do, one day you might
be reunited with your mother.
Follow me.
Episode 2
Hunters, Hunted
They haven't managed
to put out the fire yet?
Master Gakai...
This is the third time.
Three times, the prince's
life has been threatened.
So they still haven't
determined if he survived?
No.
Incidentally, Shuga...
These rumors of Prince Chagum
being possessed, are they true?
As tutor-governor
of Ichinomiya Palace...
...I like to think that I know
everything about Prince Sagum.
Well, no matter.
Even assuming that Prince Chagum
has, in fact, perished in this fire...
...perhaps it is for the best.
If the unthinkable happened and
these unpleasant rumors had spread...
...it might have greatly hampered
the government's ability to function.
If you will excuse me,
I will return to my devotions.
Come on, I'll carry you piggyback.
You're asleep on your feet.
What's the matter? Hop on.
What does this "piggyback" mean?
Piggyback means being
carried on someone's back.
Commoner children...
...are carried on the backs of their
mothers from the day they're born.
There's no shame in being carried.
Everyone grows up doing it.
Hop on.
It's warmer and more comfortable
for you this way, isn't it?
Go on and get some sleep.
It is Shuga.
I have come to ask for an audience
with the master star reader.
Why have you come?
I already know about Ninomiya Palace.
Master Star Reader...
Prince Sagum, the heir to the throne,
is not in the best of health.
One would think that Prince Chagum
would be vital to us now.
What, exactly, are you implying?
The remainder of this conversation
will take place before empty vessels.
If I may...
I believe His Majesty ordered
the death of Prince Chagum.
His death?
I prayed that
I was worrying needlessly.
But I can no longer fool myself.
His Highness began to meet with
strange accidents one after another...
...immediately after I reported
his condition to you.
The prince is
descended from the gods.
He cannot be possessed by
evil spirits under any circumstances.
Regardless of whether he was ever,
in fact, truly possessed.
But was there truly nothing
that could have been done for him?
Do not speak so glibly.
Have you forgotten the message that
the second queen sent to that...
...common magic weaver?
This is due to your hasty, reckless
actions as his tutor-governor.
However, unlike the earlier
incidents, the fire tonight...
...was not set on
the orders of His Majesty.
Shuga...
...if you focus too long on
the workings of politics and the stars...
...you will soon lose sight of
the workings of the human heart.
I had forgotten that
the second queen is also a mother.
I am told that she summoned
to Ninomiya Palace last night...
...a female bodyguard who
had saved the life of the prince.
Deducing that
her son was in danger...
...she likely used this bodyguard
to allow the prince to escape.
The fire is merely a ploy
to cover their tracks.
I doubt that you will find his body.
Then Prince Chagum is still...
But you are to speak of this to no one.
A significant number have heard
this rumor of a possessing spirit.
If Prince Chagum is believed
to have died in the fire...
...it will be convenient
for all concerned.
Incidentally, how do you believe
the prince managed to escape...
...all of those drowning
attempts so easily?
In my humble opinion, I believe that
the evil spirit possessing him...
...is in all likelihood a water demon.
By "water demon," do you
mean that water demon?
Yes.
The water demon depicted in
The Official History of Shin- Yogo...
...the chronicle of
Shin-Yogo's creation.
Shuga.
I have always greatly
valued your ability.
For that reason,
I feel that I must warn you.
Should you go on involving yourself
in the government's dark side...
...you will be going down
a path of no return.
A dark, sinister underbelly
to the star palace...
...whose existence you
most likely never suspected.
I have always been taught
that the world is composed...
...of light and darkness
in equal measure.
No matter how dark and twisted
the path may be, if it leads to heaven...
...then I should like to walk down it.
As you wish.
Let that be the one and only
light to illuminate your path.
Come with me.
With His Majesty's consent,
I have decided to dispatch pursuers.
To bring back the prince.
To what end?
Going back to my question earlier...
...it is most likely a water demon
that has possessed the prince.
That is why I intended to use fire
to try to kill it in our third attempt.
The Official History tells us that at
a spring fed by the Aoyumi River...
...Torugaru, the first mikado of
the Shin-Yogo empire...
...slew a water demon that
had possessed a Yakoo child.
Upon doing this,
he declared himself mikado...
...the son of heaven, one who
receives the blessings of the gods.
The child was possessed...
From this, we can deduce it is
impossible for anyone other than one...
...who has received heaven's blessings
to take a water demon's life.
You don't mean...
Upon Prince Chagum's return...
...the mikado himself will
slay it using Star's Heart...
...the blade passed down
from Torugaru's time.
But he cannot!
Surely that would be much too...
You need not tell me!
Behind the bamboo blinds,
His Majesty was weeping.
Even if it is for the
good of the government...
...he must take the life of his own son.
I am sure that you understand how
great the mikado's suffering must be.
These are the Hunters,
who serve the mikado in secret!
Their true identity is known
only by the mikado and myself.
And now, you will be the third to know!
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Toya?
Toya, are you there?
Balsa!
Can I come in?
Balsa.
So you're back in town?
It's been a long time, Toya.
Sorry, Saya, I didn't mean
to wake you up too.
That's all right.
I was about to get up anyway.
Oh, I see.
By the way, do you two
know where Torogai is now?
Sorry, I haven't heard anything
about her in town lately.
I see.
Never mind then. Forget I asked.
Wake up, Chagum!
Then you haven't run into Tanda yet?
He's here in town?
Yes. He said he thought you would
be coming back any day now.
Who's that?
Are you awake?
What did you do, kidnap
some nobleman's child?
Hardly.
I've been hired as
this boy's bodyguard.
Please, have a seat.
Thanks.
Go ahead.
I can't go into details with you, though.
It's quite complicated.
Toya, will you use this money
to buy a few things for me?
Just name it. I'd do anything for you,
come hell or high water.
I'm glad to hear it.
First of all, I need ten big sheets
of oiled paper to keep the rain out...
...and a bear pelt warm enough
for sleeping on a snowy mountain.
I also need ten days' worth
of dried meat and rice cakes.
Also a set of clothes
that will fit the boy.
Just leave it to me.
Is there anything else?
One last thing.
A horse that can
handle a long journey.
A horse?
This is a 10,000 Iugal gold coin!
Will buying a horse on the spot,
even for 10,000 lugals, be trouble?
Who do you think you're talking to?
Around here, I'm the most reliable
errand runner there is.
Do your legs hurt?
Here, rub this on the parts that hurt.
It'll make them feel a little better.
Can you do it yourself?
I know how to do it.
That comes to twenty Iugal.
Twenty? Oh, come on now...
How about this much?
Ten? Are you trying
to drive me out of business?
Oh, what're you talking about?
It's spring already.
If you don't sell this bear pelt now,
it'll just sit here till winter.
Sixteen.
You're a sensible man.
All right then.
Until those two get back, stay in bed.
Keep the straw mat pulled over you.
It's far better than catching a cold.
Ordinary people certainly wouldn't
be walking around with this.
If the time comes,
I'll use these, Your Majesty.
Did you see that
commotion last night?
Yes, judging from the direction,
it was at Ninomiya Palace.
I have to say it'll be
something else if somebody died.
You know, a certain
someone who lives there...
Idiot! Don't even joke about that!
I'm going to regret not having gone
straight to the blacksmith's...
Wh-What in the world?
I'm in over my head here.
But without Torogai's help, I cannot...
Chagum.
Chagum!
Are you all right?
I must have been acting
strangely once again.
Were you having
a nightmare or something?
I do not remember.
But whenever this happens,
I feel an overwhelming urge to survive.
Didn't I tell you? I won't
let you die, no matter what.
That's not what I mean.
This isn't the first time
I've experienced this.
Ever since I've been
possessed by whatever this is...
...I've felt a desire to survive,
and I don't know why.
You're throwing quite a lot
of money around, aren't you?
And now a horse too.
Are you planning to cross the
Misty Blue Mountains or something?
How is that any of your business?
You're not going to buy it?
As they say, "A weak seam
in one's travelling clothes...
...will grow into a hole
while on the road."
Nobody asked you!
Good, this will be plenty for us.
I'm glad. Also, take these.
The shop where I bought these
makes delicious lunches.
You two are really thoughtful!
Eat while we have the chance.
I'm sorry. I got everything else,
but I'm still working on the horse!
By the way, are you planning to
cross the Misty Blue Mountains?
What makes you ask that?
Well, some strange guy asked me
that while I was out shopping.
But no need to worry.
I managed to deflect his questions.
You think fast on your feet.
Don't worry about the horse any more.
We're going to have to set out soon.
I'm sorry, but you two need to
pack up your things right away too.
Balsa?
If they find out about this place,
it'll mean trouble for you two.
This is to thank you
for all you've done.
We can't take this much!
Just take it.
I'm asking you to leave your home.
This is nowhere near enough.
What? But I was the one who
couldn't come through for you...
But you mustn't use
the coins until next year.
Is that clear?
I'm sorry...
Goodbye! Take care of yourselves!
Are your legs bothering you?
Are you hungry?
I am fine.
You weren't a prince
for nothing, were you?
You have grit.
Not having a horse is going
to make this a lot tougher...
A double moon...
That's why they...
This isn't good. There's nowhere
for us to hide out here, either...
Chagum! Run!
Run, I said!
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Balsa battles the Hunters alone.
However, she is mortally
wounded by an enemy blade.
Next time, "Fight to the Death."
What does Balsa see...
Episode 3
Fight to the Death
...as her consciousness slips away?