I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
I've waited for two years, and we
haven't had the chance to talk yet!
Episode 4
Torogai's Letter
Wait! Stay a little longer!
Damn, it was too far away!
I waited for nearly a month.
Couldn't the Water Folk hang on a bit?
Perhaps proper communication
isn't possible unless I'm at the Knot.
Looks like the second prince
didn't die in that fire after all.
Still, I wonder what he meant by that?
An egg?
So, a being from Nayug laid an egg
here in this world, eh?
I have to go to the Knot right away
and talk to the Water Folk again.
I never dreamed a chance like this
would present itself in my lifetime.
What I wouldn't give to see that egg
with my own two eyes!
But first of all, I suppose I should
get rid of those pesky pups!
But I guess I can't do that.
I couldn't live with
myself if I didn't give...
...that cheeky brat of a
master star reader a piece of my mind.
Hey! Come down here!
You're a dour-looking
pair of pups, aren't you?
You'd do well to remember this.
The more beautiful the flower,
the deadlier its fragrance.
They don't always send you off
to a pleasant sleep.
You make sure that this message
gets delivered, you stupid pups.
This is Shuga, who will be
serving Your Majesty in secret.
He is rather young, is he not?
Indeed. He is the youngest
star reader in history...
...and until recently, was
tutor-governor of Ninomiya Palace.
He is that talented, then?
Shuga, in view of your talents,
you may serve in my shadow.
I shall redouble all of my efforts, Sire.
And what of the Hunters' pursuit?
They have failed.
Failed, you say?
Yes, Sire.
This is unprecedented.
Failing to carry out my command...
Was this female bodyguard
truly that formidable?
Or perhaps they were under
the water demon's protection.
I believe that may be the case, Sire.
However, while this woman
may have driven the Hunters away.
I am told that she was
gravely injured in the process.
That being the case, it is unlikely
that she could have gone far.
Grant me leave to dispatch
the remaining Hunters, and surely...
How many Hunters are still
able to perform their duties?
Including myself, there are five, Sire.
In that case, let us
try another method.
Sire?
As soon as Chagum's
viewing ceremonies are completed...
...conduct a manhunt
to appease his spirit.
We shall dispatch troops
who know nothing.
Mobilize them under the pretext
of searching for the arsonist.
Mon, that will be your cover
to operate in secret.
Yes, Sire!
Preparations to place the body
in the coffin seem to be proceeding.
I am told that Chagum's body
was never found.
And yet, they are still
preparing a coffin.
Is Chagum really dead?
Body or no body, the second prince
has indeed passed away.
Then why has the second queen
been moved to the Inner Palace?
If Chagum is indeed dead,
surely that is cruel treatment!
One who will eventually
rule this country...
...ought not concern himself
with such trivial matters.
Is it trivial to show concern for
the mother of my younger brother?
If so, then one must truly be
cold of heart to be mikado.
It is for that reason that I wanted
Chagum to live in a world...
...devoid of such callousness.
Simply watching Chagum
running and playing happily...
...raised my spirits to no end.
Become empty vessels.
What is it this time?
We have received an unusual letter
from the magic weaver.
Surely those who pursued the
magic weaver did not fail me as well.
So what is this letter?
Here it is.
Ah, I see.
Mon, I don't intend to dwell on
what is over and done with.
There is no shortage of matters that
you and your men must attend to.
For now, heal your wounds and
be ready for your next orders.
Sir!
Read it. It is addressed to you as well.
To my dear star readers...
...who, rather than gaze at the stars,
instead fix their gaze on their feet.
Ignoring the nature of the being
that resides in the second prince...
...will result in a terrible
drought afflicting this land.
Your ancestors had the capacity
to work for a common cause.
Though it pains me to say so,
we Yakoo have also...
...misplaced something vital
in the depths of time.
I shall now go forth to visit one
who knows the truth of this matter.
Until I return, I suggest you refrain
from taking any rash action.
How do you interpret this letter?
Torogai is already aware of
the sign of the great drought...
...and is about to undertake an
investigation to further study its cause.
That is how I interpret it.
Master, I believe we should work
with the Yakoo magic weavers...
...and conduct an exchange
of knowledge with them.
Exchange knowledge with them?
Reveal all to the magic Weavers?
The very thought is outrageous!
Star readers must never go to
magic weavers in search of advice!
But they are more knowledgeable on...
Do not forget...
...that the honor of Shin-Yogo
hangs in the balance.
Nevertheless, I do not suggest that
we attempt to slay the prince...
...and the water demon
that possesses him.
Here in the Star Palace...
...there is a storehouse which only
the master star readers know of.
In that room lie epistles left behind
by grand master star reader Nanai...
...who played such a pivotal role
in the founding of the country.
However, being written in
the ancient Yogo tongue...
...deciphering them all will take
considerable time and effort.
Shuga, you are hereby relieved
of your duties as star reader.
To prevent the drought likely to befall
our country in the near future...
...I charge you with the task
of deciphering the epistles.
Decipher the epistles
and find a means...
...of vanquishing the water demon
before the magic weaver does.
A way to vanquish the water demon...
I am honored to accept this task
of deciphering the epistles.
Report to me everything
that you uncover.
I have every faith in you.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Well, I've managed to patch you up...
What in the world
happened to you, Balsa?
Tanda!
Now I understand.
I'm sorry. I can't do anything right.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
It isn't your fault.
It's her own fault for
being so reckless.
Still, going by what you've told me...
...I suppose that would make this boy
the prince of Ninomiya Palace.
Jiguro?
You?
What are you doing here?
How long have I been unconscious?
It hasn't even been a full day yet.
A day?
Tanda, did you sense anyone
around where you found me?
All I saw there were your footprints
and drops of your blood.
Oh...
I've heard about your situation.
You should really thank these two.
Toya...thanks.
Tanda, did anything
happen to the boy?
Not really.
More importantly, is he really...
I didn't want to get you involved in all this.
As you've probably guessed,
he's Shin-Yogo's second prince.
His name is Chagum.
Because he's been
possessed by a spirit...
...the Mikado considers him tainted
and has ordered him to be killed.
And that's why the second queen
hired me as his bodyguard.
And this is the outcome.
You're really hopeless!
Look, I want to help him
as much as the next person, but...
Tanda, I want you to
find out what that spirit is.
If possible, I'd like you to
remove it from him.
A spirit, you say? I don't know...
Your master's the only one
who can handle it, then?
I didn't say that I couldn't do it!
Here, let me take a quick look.
What is it?
I have a feeling that
I'm in over my head here.
I see.
But it seems to be something
that came from Nayug.
Meaning we'll need to have
Torogai take a look, after all.
Yes, but she's out drifting
wherever the wind takes her again.
You're right...
Tanda.
Do you have any food
that will help me recover?
There's no time to spare.
How long will it take
this wound to heal?
Don't be ridiculous.
It'll take even you ten days.
Seven if we're being optimistic...
I can't wait that long.
They might be at
our throats any minute.
Please do something!
I can't bear to cause you
any more trouble.
When did we say anything
about you troubling us?
I'll feed you properly.
And I'll protect you from your pursuers.
So stop worrying and
focus on getting better.
Thank you...
You don't have to worry.
Go ahead and sleep too.
This time of year, there are plenty of
herbs that are good for wounds.
This old lady and I have known
each other for twenty years.
She gets herself torn up like she
is now and ends up at my door.
Ever since we were children,
it's been one fight after another...
...and I'd tend to
her injuries every time.
She's a woman, but her body's
covered in a patchwork of scars.
And thanks to that, I must say
I'm adept at stitching up wounds now...
...and I've picked up quite a bit
about medicinal herbs too.
Has Balsa been a bodyguard
ever since she was a child?
Oh, no. When we were small,
she trained from sunup to sundown.
It was about six years ago that she
started working as a bodyguard.
Has it already been that long?
The truth is, Balsa saved
my life and Saya's too.
We're both orphans, so there aren't
any adults who look out for us.
I've raised Saya as my sister,
but then slave traders tried to take her.
And that's when Balsa
showed up and saved the day.
Without even taking off
the sheath of her spear...
...she dispatched all six of them
in the blink of an eye.
Really... She's a
powerful lady, this one...
She's put that strength to good use,
saving countless people.
And in the process,
I've also taken lots of lives.
You're awake, then?
Balsa! Are you all right?
No, not really. I'm aching all over.
But I'll be better soon.
It's time to change your
bandages and salves.
Really, you heal amazingly
quickly for a middle-aged lady.
Will I be up and around
sooner than you thought?
Not a chance.
Even if the wound is closed...
...the cut flesh and muscle
won't be good as new right away.
I remember this scar!
This is the very first cut
that I ever stitched.
As I recall, you were crying
your eyes out at the time.
Fool!
Stop it. That tickles!
What's the matter?
Something strange is
happening to my stomach.
What?
I've never seen such a prince!
You couldn't even tell you were hungry?
This is what hunger feels like?
How odd.
This tastes far better than
anything I ate at the palace.
You think so?
Who's there!
An egg... An egg...
Mistress Torogai!
An egg...
An egg... An egg...
The egg!
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
That which resides within Chagum
is the egg of a spirit.
To unravel its mysteries, the door
to the Chamber of the Epistles opens.
Next time,
"Secret Plan, The Blue Hand."
Episode 5
Secret Plan, The Blue Hand
Balsa, can you break
the net that encircles you?