I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Who's there!
An egg... An egg...
An egg...
The egg!
Episode 5
Secret Plan, The Blue Hand.
How did this come to be here?
You're the second prince, aren't you?
Balsa...
Balsa?
Ah, so I see!
The second queen was
quite clever, wasn't she?
You were hired to be
this boy's bodyguard?
Torogai, this boy is...
Oh, how lucky I am!
To think that something
that might appear...
...only once in a hundred years
would fall into my lap!
I'm going to take a quick look.
Master!
What we're dealing with here
is an egg, all right.
I've only heard stories
about these until now.
To think that I'd see one
with my own eyes...
W-Wait a minute!
Interacting with Nayug is
indeed no easy matter...
Master, what in the world is...
That is the egg of Nyunga Ro Im.
An egg?
What is a...whatever you said?
A Nyunga Ro Im is a creature said
to drink the waters of Sagu dry.
It's what the people of Yogo
would call a water demon.
We Yakoo, on the other hand,
call it the spirit of the water.
It sounds like I made
the right call in coming here.
Torogai, can you do anything
to remove this egg or whatever it is?
Probably not.
The second queen asked me
the very same question.
Nayug and Sagu overlap,
supporting each ether's existence.
But it is no simple matter
to interact between the two.
If memory serves, in the Yakoo tongue,
Sagu means "this world."
That being the case, does Nayug
then mean "the other world"?
Honestly, this is why I don't
care much for amateurs.
Now, now, Master...
When was the egg laid inside you?
I have no memory of it happening...
...but strange things began to happen
around the beginning of spring.
Ah, I see.
If so, it must have been around
the full moon of the first lunar month.
You see, it is said that
Nayug and Sagu...
...are powerfully drawn to
each other during full moons.
How ironic.
Torugaru slew a water spirit
to create this nation.
And now his descendant
bears the egg of one...
...and is at risk of being killed by
his own father because of it.
Still, that Nyunga Ro lm was foolish.
Laying its egg inside a prince would
so clearly put the egg in danger!
Tell me, how does it feel to be
a Nyunga Ro Chaga?
Torogai...
...would you mind explaining things
in terms that we can all understand?
Unlike you, the rest of us
aren't schooled in the arts.
That was tactfully put.
Very well, I'll explain it so that
even a nitwit could understand.
Translated into the tongue of Yogo...
...Nyunga Ro Chaga would
mean "guardian of the spirit."
Guardian of the spirit?
Simply put, it refers to the person
who has been given the duty...
...of safeguarding the egg
until it hatches.
But look what happened...
What in the world is going on?
But wait a moment...
I do not feel well.
I shall go get some fresh air.
Tanda, I am going to the Knot.
The Knot? The place where
Nayug and Sagu intersect?
Exactly.
Unless I connect with the Water Folk
and have a proper discussion...
...I think things are
going to get quite nasty.
Get ready to set out at once!
With all due respect...
...Balsa is injured,
and if I leave with you, she might...
What, are you saying
that you can't go?
Well, I suppose we can't have
the egg fall into the mikado's hands.
What is your plan, Balsa?
I've been mulling that over
for a while now.
Judging from the fact that no pursuers
have followed us here...
...the mikado must have chosen a
different means of capturing Chagum.
The men I fought were likely
the mikado's first, most powerful card.
You mean those youngsters
in the black outfits?
I'm surprised you know about them.
Oh, they paid me a little visit as well.
Of course, I beat them at their own game.
I'm impressed.
As you should be. So what would be
the mikado's next move?
Let's see. What if he told everyone
that Chagum died in the fire?
He's probably kept
his activities secret so far...
...but this might free him up
to take more forceful action.
What sort of forceful action?
Are you all right? Do you feel sick?
Hey, if you touch him, you'll...
Torogai doesn't mince any words,
but she's a powerful magic weaver.
I'm sure that she'll
find a way to help you.
That boy doesn't have the least
bit of talent for magic weaving...
...but he's making fine progress
when it comes to treating injuries.
Probably because a certain
tomboy was always...
...covered in bumps and bruises
ever since she was a little girl.
Well, no matter. But what
do you plan to do now?
Look after His Highness out there
for the rest of your life?
Just like Jiguro did for you?
It's not such a bad sentiment
to try to save the lives of others...
...to appease the souls lost
in the process of saving your own.
So, how many lives
have you saved so far?
Could we please drop this?
No, we can't!
How many lives have you taken
for those you've saved?
The lives of ten people?
Twenty people?
Or has it been fifty?
Since I left this place, not one.
You don't say...
It was because you'd had
a fight with Tanda over that...
...that you left here
two years ago, as I recall.
Balsa. What you think of the
lives of others is entirely up to you.
But in this one instance,
you might not have that luxury.
If, as the legends say,
that egg hatches into a water spirit...
...it's highly likely that this land
will be struck by a terrible drought.
If that happens, the number of lives
you carry on your shoulders...
...will include the millions of Yogo
and Yakoo people who live here.
Do you still insist on protecting
the prince with those lives at stake?
Yes.
I'll save him, and see
what I can do about the rest.
What a hopeless fool you are...
You'll be safe if you stay inside the hut.
Is it nearby?
Yes. It sounds like it's a wolf
that's strayed from its pack.
Everyone, listen to
what I'm about to say.
Due to my current condition...
...I'm going to divide up some jobs
that I want you to do for me.
If things work out
according to my plan...
...we'll be able to throw
our pursuers completely off our trail.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
She said she was
going to split up the work...
...so why are Saya and I
the only ones getting kicked out?
I wouldn't call this being kicked out.
You're going to be laying low
in Yashiro Village for a while, that's all.
My uncle's house is there.
Relax. Balsa won't steer you wrong.
I know that, but we'd do anything
for Balsa! Come hell or high water!
She shouldn't be so protective of us.
What do you think is going on?
No idea.
Excuse me, has something happened?
What, you haven't heard?
It's a manhunt.
The call suddenly came
down from the palace.
A manhunt?
You know about that fire that
killed the prince at Ninomiya Palace?
Yes.
Word has it that the fire was set
by some woman from Kanbal.
Her name was Balsa
or something like that.
Anyway, they said that the
manhunt forces are mobilizing...
...tomorrow morning to capture her.
We're covering all ground from
the Torinaki River to Yashiro Village!
Tanda!
I see it. If they're conscripting
even the farmers from this area...
...this manhunt will be more
than one or two hundred strong.
You two go back to the hut.
Tell Balsa what's happening here.
What's the matter?
This is exactly what you wanted!
Right!
Come on, Saya, let's go!
The Chamber of the Epistles,
from which even the mikado is barred...
Ancient Yogo script...
These are all epistles?
This must be the spot.
Thank goodness. They're still here.
Excuse me?
I'm sorry, sir.
We're in mourning today,
so we aren't conducting any business.
My apologies. I'm aware of that...
...but I was told that if I came here,
you would hear me out.
Hear you out?
Yes. Forgive me if this seems abrupt...
...but this establishment is
known as the Blue Hand, isn't it?
Sir, if I might ask,
where did you hear that name?
Well, from an acquaintance...
And what is the name of this
acquaintance of yours, if you don't mind?
I don't mind at all. Her name is Balsa.
Balsa the Spear-wielder? That Balsa?
Yes, that's right.
Listen, you! What's your
connection to that spear-wielder?
Depending on your story,
you might not walk out of here alive!
Sir, what business does
Balsa the Spear-wielder have with us?
Well, she says that she wants to
buy all of your merchandise.
That's hardly unusual, is it?
Curse that woman!
Is she out of her mind?
Time after time she's
hindered our business...
...and now she wants to buy from us?
Who do you think you are?
You're a dead man!
Why are you so upset by this?
Does it always upset you to have
someone buy your merchandise?
Listen, you.
You keep casually throwing around
the word "merchandise."
Do you know what sort of
merchandise we deal in here?
No, I wasn't told that part.
Our business dealings center around
the buying and selling of people.
So that means that our
stock in trade is human beings.
How can you be so calm about this?
The manhunt forces won't get started
until tomorrow morning, right?
Yes, but we're talking about
some serious forces out there.
He's right. If they all
came at us at once, we'd...
I hope they do.
Ah, here they are.
What's the meaning of this?
We hear that it was you who
reduced Ninomiya Palace to ashes...
...and now you want to buy people
from us with palace crest gems.
Would you care to explain yourself?
Please, come on in.
What's so funny?
We can pay you back for all
you've done to us right now!
Oh? And do what?
Run to the palace, treasure in hand?
I can't do that, and you know it.
Then let's talk business.
How's your stock looking right now?
I've got 30 people on hand.
A few of them are Yogo natives.
The rest are foreigners.
Very well. I'll take them
all off your hands.
Are you serious?
What the hell are you planning?
Those gems are your payment.
I trust you'll be able to circulate them?
Just a minute, Balsa!
Those gems represent
a mother's love for her child!
I'm perfectly aware of that.
That's why this is the time to use them.
So, what do you want us to do?
Deliver them all to you here?
That won't be necessary.
Just unlock the door to your hideout.
Tomorrow morning, set free
all of the people you're holding.
And that's the end of your duties.
Isn't that an easy job?
So that's it. I can tell what you're up to!
This should be interesting.
It's going to cause no end of trouble
for the manhunt forces, however.
I see you've gotten
smarter over the years.
But listen, if you recapture the people
you've freed, you'll pay dearly.
You can trust us. This is business.
I won't pry into what you've done,
but come back when it's all over.
This time for sure,
let's team up and get rich together.
Please, let's not even joke about that.
This isn't part of the deal,
but that horse of yours...
Judging from the sound of its hooves,
is it a Kokkou stallion...
...said to be able to gallop across
three kingdoms in a single night?
You have sharp ears.
I thought as much.
Then I'll help myself to the horse too.
Absolutely not!
That's one order I can't fulfill.
You owe me for this, understand?
That's Balsa for you! She's amazing!
You look like you want to
get something off your chest.
No, I was just thinking to myself
that you're as amazing as ever.
For as long as I've known you,
you've always been self-reliant.
But...
...at times like this, you should
ask me for help, damn it!
Get out.
You're free.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
The secret plan is a success...
...and Balsa slips past the manhunt.
Or rather, it appeared that she did.
Next time,
"To Die in the Misty Blue."
Episode 6
To Die in the Misty Blue
Two bodies vanish into the ravine...