I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Episode 6
To Die in the Misty Blue
Now I look nothing at all like a prince.
Are you sure that you'll be all right?
Yes.
Torogai?
I've decided to leave with them.
Master, where did you
get that donkey?
I'm going to build up his legs
until he's good and sturdy.
Tell your uncle I said that.
Let's go.
Balsa.
Thank you for everything,
Make sure that you
don't catch cold. Take care.
Balsa.
Don't get yourself killed.
Right.
As long as you stand there paralyzed
by your lingering affections...
...the more their chances
of dying increase!
Such a fool!
At that pace,
I doubt that they'll make it...
...to the Misty Blue Pass
before the sun goes down.
We have 100 men between her last
known location and Yashiro village...
...and 350 men on
each of the mountains...
...that divide the Aoyumi
into east and west.
They have been ordered
to search for her.
Reports suggest that the woman
appears to be gravely injured.
I do not believe that
locating her will prove difficult.
What makes you so certain?
Sir?
I have a report, sir!
We have had reports
from the Yashiro village area...
...that last night some farmers saw
what appeared to be a Kanbal woman.
What direction was
this woman headed?
As for that... Some farmers claimed
that she was traveling to the west...
...while other reports say
that she was heading south.
She's doubling back
towards Kosenkyo?
We've located her!
Where?
There are reports of a
suspicious-looking woman...
...being spotted in the lands
east of the Yakoo rice terraces.
To the east this time?
Commander?
Send the men who left
to join the manhunt to the east!
No, to the west as well! And assign
lookouts to Kosenkyo's city gates!
Yes, sir!
Follow me!
It looks like the woman anticipated
that there would be a manhunt for her.
These multiple sightings
are most likely a diversion.
What do you two think?
I believe them to be
a diversion as well.
I concur.
As do I.
I believe that to be the case as well.
I thought I ordered you
to get some rest.
Lying still doing nothing
only frustrates me.
I believe it only slows down
the healing process.
There is but one option
left open to us.
And that is to deduce
what that woman is thinking.
We put ourselves in her place...
...and we deduce what action
she is likely to take.
Perhaps I am physically incompetent...
...but my mind is in
perfect working order!
Taga and Sune, gather the intelligence
that has come to the manhunt teams.
Yes, sir!
Zen, Yun, and Jin, the rest of us
will analyze that woman's thoughts!
Yes, sir!
The first order of business is
to counter the woman's next ploy...
...with a certain and resolute
move of our own.
Let us determine what path
the woman is taking!
Begin silent meditation!
About those hunting dogs
that attacked us both...
As you say, surely there can't be
a great number of men of that caliber.
That said, those people are tenacious.
They'll keep coming and coming
until that boy is dead.
No need to worry.
If you can manage to give them the slip,
you'll live to see the next spring.
Chances are, that egg
won't hatch anytime soon.
Eggs don't hatch until what's inside
has developed to a certain degree...
...and is fully prepared to emerge
and face the outside world.
From what I saw, the egg inside you
hasn't finished its preparations yet.
I will go and find us some answers.
Make sure that you
get away safely, you hear?
Good luck to your own task, then.
Magmmmm
Hey! You there!
The north. The woman will
cross the Misty Blue Mountains.
My conclusion was north as well.
She was born in Kanbal.
She will go north.
Yes, but she is wounded.
And that wound is no mere scratch.
And most importantly,
the prince is with her.
At a glance, it certainly appears
to be a suicidal move.
A wise man would avoid
the Misty Blue Mountains.
That is the conclusion that
she expects us to make.
She will do the opposite and
will go to the Misty Blue Mountains.
That's right.
Misdirection is commonly employed
by any skilled tactician.
True. During our skirmish,
she feigned escape.
She also discarded her spear and
instead attacked with a throwing stone.
She misled us both times.
But you could say she merely used
any means necessary for her goal.
There is one thing
that does concern me.
That she refused to strike
any of us with a fatal blow...
Under those circumstances,
we all could have been struck dead.
If that was another case of subterfuge
meant to throw us into confusion...
...then it is entirely possible that
she will double back and go south.
Jin.
That detail has troubled me
ever since the battle as well.
This is a woman who will stop
at nothing to escape with the prince...
...so why is it that she did not kill us?
Surely that would have been the
soundest course of action, and yet...
It is most baffling.
And yet, I think there was some other
motive at work behind that action...
...that is separate from her objective
of escaping with the prince.
In which case,
the woman's destination is...
Commander!
The manhunt teams have
received reports of a woman...
...resembling a Kanbal native
heading west on the Tosei highway.
That is a diversion.
We just concluded that she is
going to the Misty Blue Mountains.
But sir, they say that she is carrying
what appears to be a short spear...
...and, what is most noteworthy,
she has a child in tow.
Well played. Not only has that woman
divided the manhunt's forces...
...she's also kept us pinned down here.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Are you in pain?
I'm all right.
For the time being anyway.
What did I tell you? Aren't you glad
we didn't join the manhunt teams?
I knew all along that
she was going to go west.
Commander! Please, follow the path
that you believe to be best.
I will take Taga with me and
scour the road to the west.
Therefore, you...
I'll go. You're in no condition to ride.
But I...
She may be our enemy,
but I admire this woman.
If the woman on the road
does indeed turn out to be her...
...use blowgun darts
dipped in poison to kill her.
Whatever you do,
don't get inside her striking range.
Yes, sir!
Zen.
You and I will make for
the Misty Blue Mountains.
Excuse us.
Can I help you?
Has a woman been by here?
An injured woman?
Oh, yes, plenty of them.
Because of my profession, you see.
But every woman I receive is gone...
...the moment their business
with me is concluded.
Well, why not?
Why come to me unless
they need medicinal herbs?
Even a man like me knows that
it's a man's role to keep women safe.
But for as long as I can remember...
...it's the girl who's always gotten
herself hurt and always ends up here...
...so what can I do?
No wonder my first thought is
always to heal her wounds...
Am I wrong?
Forgive us. Perhaps our
question was inappropriate.
Commander?
The front hoof prints aren't
the same size as the back ones.
A Kokkou stallion, eh?
Even a horse that can gallop
across three kingdoms in one night...
...is of no use if you don't let it run.
We shall capture them before nightfall!
Yes, sir!
The mountains seem
farther away than ever.
Is Kanbal really that far away?
Kanbal lies beyond the mountains
beyond that mountain.
We've a long way to go.
Are you tired?
Balsa...
What sort of place is Kanbal?
Well...
Compared to Yogo, it's a harsh place.
The air is thin there,
and the soil is rocky and barren.
But there are meadows where
you can give free rein to your horse.
Once you're there,
it's not such a bad place.
Does your family live there, Balsa?
Balsa?
Cut across the stream!
The paths branch off for a while, but...
...there's an outcropping ahead
where you can get back onto this trail!
Do whatever it takes
to get there ahead of her!
Yes, sir!
Balsa!
Go faster!
I have you now, Spear-wielder!
Commander!
It's no use!
But the prince!
I know that, sir! But we can't
afford to have you die here too!
I was sure that a horse like that would
be able to climb back up on his own.
Forgive me.
This arrived from the Hunters.
When the time is right,
I shall inform the mikado myself.
You may go.
Yes, sir.
Master Shuga!
Master Shuga, this is for you!
Do you have any medicine?
You said you'd gore me to death
if I followed you, so I could only wait.
What am I, a warrior's wife?
So, I see you're still
in one piece, Balsa.
Sorry about that.
For now, though,
I just want to get a little sleep.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Chagum tries to acclimate himself
to the life of a commoner.
A vague sense of unease
begins to blossom in his young heart.
Next time,
"Chagum's Resolve."
Episode 7
Chagum's Resolve
The waterwheel turns...
...carrying his emotions with it.