I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Nothing's happened since that night.
Still, it's incredible
that we survived at all.
Episode 7
Chagum's Resolve
See to it that Chagum's image
is engraved here.
With all due respect...
Yes, I know.
I am well aware that only those
who held the rank of mikado...
...are permitted to have their likeness
engraved in stone for perpetuity.
Let them mock me as
a foolish father. I care not.
But it was Chagum's death that spared
this country from the water demon.
If his noble sacrifice does not warrant
being remembered forever, what does?
Yes, my lord.
The sign of the great drought
should lift now.
I see. So that's how things
turned out yesterday?
That's right. For now, at least,
there's nothing to be done about it.
I'm just thankful to be
here with you now.
You don't like noisy crowds?
I find the vigor of the
common people most appealing.
It is not at all unpleasant.
Chagum, regular townsfolk
don't speak like that.
Did you find something?
Yes. It's quite a hidden gem.
When can we move in?
You can move in right away.
All that's left for you to do is pay for it.
I'll have the same, please.
I told Toya and Saya everything.
Did you now?
They were both pretty angry.
Well, I did cause
a lot of trouble for them.
How are they doing?
Toya is anxious to come back to town.
He's a townsman
through and through.
But it's still too soon.
Let's eat, shall we?
You know, Balsa, the whole town
is full of gossip about you now.
No one would ever guess that
the subject of their gossip...
...would be sitting here having lunch.
Maybe so, but...
Care to put it to the test?
Excuse me, sir?
What do you want?
Have you heard of a bodyguard
who goes by the name...
...Balsa the Spear-wielder?
Balsa, did you say?
She's the talk of the town
at the moment.
Let me guess,
you're new in town, aren't you?
You could say that.
If you're so curious about her,
I can tell you all that you want to know.
She's a dastardly villain
who set fire to the palace...
...killed the prince and then died in a
huge battle against a thousand pursuers.
You don't say! How incredible!
Damned right. But as someone
who's crossed swords with her before...
...I have to say her demise
was rather anticlimactic.
Oh, my! You mean you've
fought this Balsa person?
That's right! She may have
been a female bodyguard...
...but she was more ferocious
than any man I've ever met.
Her spear attacks
were so overwhelming...
...that even I could
just barely earn a draw.
I had always hoped to settle
the score with her one day...
...but now I'll never get the chance.
You're unbelievable!
Yes, I am!
See?
This is a dish called "gisho."
Gisho?
This is what they serve a Yakoo man
who won't be taking over...
...as head of his family
to celebrate his having established...
...a family of his own.
A family...
The Yakoo place a high value
on celebrations like this.
These big fava beans
represent the father.
The red, slender beans
are the mother.
And the little yellow
chickpeas are the child.
If you say so...
Shuga.
There is no longer any need
to decipher the epistles.
You may return to
your star reader duties.
How powerless I am...
How incompetent I am...
I wasn't able to accomplish
anything at all.
Thank you for your hard work.
I'll be taking a bit of a shortcut,
so this is where we part company.
This should keep the wolves away,
but be careful all the same.
Take care.
Off with you.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Come to think of it...
...if this was any of your previous jobs,
you'd be done at this point.
You would be done?
In the bodyguard business...
...the job is typically over once
you've driven off your enemies.
Mind if we make a quick stop here?
I'm all out of herbs
for treating wounds.
Good afternoon.
Welcome, sir.
I'd like some of my usual medicinal
herbs if you have them in stock.
Right this way.
Don't touch that without asking.
You're done already?
He's getting what I need
from his storeroom.
Listen, are you sure you're up to
handling things from now on?
Handle what?
Looking after someone
your whole life...
...is basically the same
as being a mother.
Now that you mention it,
I suppose it is.
How long have you been
an herbologist, Tanda?
Let me think...
I guess I started mixing
medicines when I was 12...
...using the reference guides
my mentor made.
Then you started working
at quite a young age.
I was the youngest child.
I had to learn self-reliance...
...so that I'd be able to
earn my own living one day.
Well, I'll catch up
with you after I make...
...a quick trip back and
buy the rest of what I need.
All right.
Where are we going?
To pay the rent.
Rent?
Commoners cannot stay in their homes
unless they pay money to do so?
You can't get anything
if you don't pay for it with money.
I understand the concept
of exchanging money for goods.
I also understand
paying money for services...
...like when you were
paid money to protect me.
But...
I paid money at the inn, remember?
One pays money even to sleep?
But it was I who slept, not you!
I couldn't take a client's money
if I slept on the job.
To a commoner, money rules
all aspects of life, does it not?
You could say that.
And we've handed over all of
the treasure given to us by Mother.
I can rest easy now. You seem like
an honest, upstanding family to me.
Forgive me, but the boy
is someone else's child.
Due to various circumstances,
he was left in our care.
I see. Taking in someone else's
child is no trivial matter.
That speaks well of you too.
I hope you will find this acceptable.
There's no need to be so generous.
After all, I might not live out the term
that this much money will cover.
Of course, if my wife were still alive...
...I wouldn't have to impose on
my daughter and her family.
Forgive my useless rambling.
Take good care of the place.
We will.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I wonder how Jiguro felt
when he was in this position?
I suppose when you're
raised by a man of few words...
...you grow up to be
a silent person yourself.
But that won't do, will it?
This is the house that we
will be living in from now on.
We are going to take up
residence here?
That's right.
I never would've guessed one would
pay in gold coins to live in a water mill.
It's a hidden gem, that's for certain.
Why don't we give it a try?
Who knows, it might be fun.
You know how to operate
a waterwheel, Balsa?
Oh, yes. isn't it nice to be living in
a house that has devices like this?
I think the roof might need
to be thatched again, though.
I think you may be right.
But I expect that will cost money too.
I'm back.
You bought too much.
Don't worry about it.
Sorry I took so long.
I wanted to treat you two to a fine meal...
...and by the time I'd bought
everything, it had gotten late.
It'll be ready in no time.
Chagum, do you feel sick?
No, I am fine.
I am in good health thanks to you.
You've been through quite an ordeal
over these past few days.
There's no harm in filling yourself up
with a hearty meal for once.
There is something that I wish
to discuss with the two of you.
I thank you for all that
you have done for me.
Please accept this earring
as a token of my gratitude.
I owe you a debt of gratitude that
I shall never forget as long as I live.
I cannot bring myself to
impose on you any longer.
I have decided that from
today forward, I shall fend for myself.
I thought you'd been acting funny...
So is that what you've
been brooding over all day?
I guess I shouldn't be surprised.
You find this amusing?
Chagum, how would you
support yourself if you left us now?
It may not be as extensive as Tanda's...
...but I have knowledge of
medicines and animals as well.
I will get by somehow.
You silly boy...
You can stay here as long as you like.
When I met your mother,
that's what I promised her, remember?
And besides, there are
lots of people in this world...
...who wouldn't turn away a boy like you
even if they weren't paid to take you in.
But money is needed
to survive, is it not?
Don't worry. There's no need for you
to give that a moment's thought.
Thank you, Balsa...
The sign of the great drought
has not disappeared!
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
A visit is paid to Balsa's
longstanding blacksmith.
There they are reunited...
...with someone unexpected.
Someone other than the blacksmith.
Next time,
"The Swordsmith."
Episode 8
The Swordsmith
What is it that qualifies one...
...to wield the ultimate blade?