I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Good morning.
Finally awake, huh?
Go and wash your face.
Then we'll have breakfast.
After that, there's a place
that we need to go today.
Plus, you need to learn how
people in the town live.
I'm going to have this looked at,
so come with me to Ogi no Shimo.
Very well. So, where does one go
to have a spear serviced?
To a swordsmith.
Episode 8
The Swordsmith
I had no idea that there were this many
smiths to be found in Kosenkyo.
That's because Yogo steel
is famous in Rota, Sangal...
...and even in my home
country of Kanbal.
Don't tell me you didn't know that?
I have been taught that Yogo steel is a
vital trade commodity for our country...
...but also that I should not view the
steel actually being melted and worked.
Now that you mention it, it's ancient
tradition among the Yogo aristocracy...
...that warriors who see a sword
being forged can never become powerful.
Well, you're on your way to see
a blade being forged...
...so I suppose you'll never
become powerful now.
What about you, Balsa?
Have you never seen
a sword being forged?
Ever since I was little,
I've loved to watch steel...
...that's been heated red-hot
and see sparks flying everywhere.
I've seen it countless times by now.
Then again, I'm neither
from Yogo nor an aristocrat...
...so maybe it doesn't apply to me.
You still don't speak like a town child...
...so sit and watch silently
once we go inside.
Very well.
Balsa...
I've been away from Yogo for a while.
As usual, I've been
living dangerously...
...but perhaps by the luck of the devil,
I've managed to survive.
You don't say.
If I may get right down to business...
would you mind taking a look?
It looks like I will have
to forge you a new one.
I see. In that case, I'd like to have
it made as quickly as possible.
Before I start, there is a
question that I must ask you.
Yes?
You've heard the rumors
around town, I take it?
More or less.
I don't want to believe that
these rumors could be true.
But if you have indeed taken up
arms against the court, then as a man...
...who supplies the court with swords,
I cannot ally myself with you.
If you can explain your actions,
I'd like to hear it before proceeding.
No, it is true that I have
taken up arms against the court.
In that case, I must inform them
that you are still alive.
I suppose that would be
the right thing to do.
What will you do, now?
Strike me down to silence me?
If you intend to report me,
I'll have no choice.
But until I get you to forge
a new spearhead for me...
...I'm going to stay right here.
You're putting me
in an awkward position.
I'm well aware how stubborn you are,
but I'm even more stubborn than you.
I can't do what you ask
until I know the full story.
Who is the boy?
For various reasons,
he's been left in my care.
By the way...
Do you know what the town's
gossip mongers are saying about Balsa?
Not really.
That she's a miscreant who will do
absolutely anything for money.
They're spreading rumors
that the prince...
...actually died at the hands of
a certain female bodyguard.
How dare they!
Balsa would never do such a...
Enough.
The truth is, I have other clients
scheduled to arrive soon...
...to pick up their finished swords.
If you insist on staying here...
...would you at least do me the favor
of waiting in the other room?
I will hear both sides of the story.
Hello?
Come in.
Excuse us.
You are right on time.
It looks like we interrupted you
while you were working.
I know that neither of you
pay any heed to superstitions...
...but I thought it would
be good manners.
That's quite all right.
Please, continue.
The recent manhunt must
have been a difficult business.
Why do you think that?
The swords you left with me
were notched quite badly.
I see. But we serve in the
imperial guard in the palace.
As I hear it, she was killed by the farmer
soldiers who were scouring the mountains.
The wear and tear on those swords is
due to constant use in training sessions.
Oh, so that's it.
Judging from their condition,
there would appear to be...
...skilled swordsmen in the guard
that I am unaware of.
It is for that reason that we requested
that you forge new swords with edges...
...of jewel steel, which absorbs impact
better than normal steel.
I don't mean to sound abrupt, but we
would like to see the swords right away.
Of course.
Your swords are waiting
in that room over there.
Wait a moment.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Before you look at the swords...
...there is something that
I must ask the two of you.
What is it?
Why the sudden formality?
What makes a Yogo sword so special?
Surely you would know the answer
to that better than anyone.
It is my understanding that Yogo blades
are swords that are rarely seen...
...that successfully merge two
normally contradictory qualities.
Suppleness that prevents breaking,
and sharpness of edge.
To go further, it is their shape,
heft, length, and curvature...
Each of these factors
has been refined over 1,000 years...
...and has already been perfected
for their wielders.
After all this time, we warriors
see them as simply weapons.
Both of your opinions
are perfectly reasonable.
What is your opinion on the matter?
What makes Yogo swords special?
Here is what I think.
In other countries, swords are
thought of as nothing more...
...than tools meant to
wound or kill others.
But in Yogo, our tradition is that
their creation and use are to be based...
...on a foundation of mutual trust
between warrior and blacksmith.
I believe that in this relationship there is
the potential to create an ultimate sword.
Ultimate sword?
Yes.
I see. Every sword you forge is praised
as a masterpiece among masterpieces.
Masterpieces? Far from it.
They say that when someone
grips the hilt of a sword I've made...
...he is suddenly consumed by
the urge to kill someone with it.
So they are no more than
instruments of calamity.
But a sword that kills no one,
severing only the bonds of karma...
That is what I consider
to be the ultimate sword.
To forge such a sword one day...
That thought is always on my mind.
However, it is no easy task.
A great sword is achieved when
both warrior and blacksmith...
...have reached the
pinnacle of their craft.
When that balance has broken down...
...that is when a so-called
cursed sword is born.
It is for that reason that I am selective
about whom I forge a sword for.
Or rather, that I must be selective.
Perhaps, but how many warriors
are there in this world...
...that might inspire you
to forge such a sword?
Let me think... In all my years,
there has been exactly one.
Only one that I felt may have
achieved the pinnacle of his craft.
You are saying that this warrior
met your standards?
I used all of the skill that I had
at my disposal at the time...
...to forge a sword for this person.
What sort of man was he?
As a fellow student of the sword arts,
you have piqued my curiosity.
Will you tell us about this person?
It was 24 years ago.
This person was a warrior
of a distant land...
...constantly on the road,
traveling from country to country.
His mastery of his weapon was such
that I had never before witnessed.
And although completely at odds with
his appearance, there was a child...
...who was constantly
at this warrior's side.
A child?
Apparently, a friend who had fallen
victim to some sort of palace intrigue...
...had entrusted his child to him.
It was because of this that the warrior
was driven out of his home country.
Immediately afterwards...
...several assassins were
dispatched to kill the warrior.
And so he came to me...
...saying that he wanted me to forge
him a sword to fight these assassins.
At first, I turned him down.
I said that I had no interest in forging
a sword for some foreigner...
...who didn't know the first thing
about Yogo swords.
But then, something made you
change your mind.
Yes. He told me of the assassins
who were sent to kill him.
Told me what sort of men they were.
When he told me this story,
my heart was moved.
They gathered the land's bravest fighters
and sent the most skilled assassins?
No... Although indeed
they were the bravest...
...the men sent to kill him were
all dear friends of the warrior...
...people with whom he had shared
both sadness and joy.
As he kept the child safe...
...the warrior was forced to slay
his former best friends...
...one by one with his own hands.
The man who sent the assassins
must have thought a great deal...
...about what would cause
the warrior the most suffering.
And the assassins had just as little
desire to hunt down the warrior.
But each of their families
was being held hostage.
And so, left with no choice,
they came to kill the warrior.
What a despicable act...
When I heard his story,
this is the thought that struck me.
That I wanted to forge the
ultimate sword for this man.
I wanted him to cut himself
free of his cruel fate...
To sever the bonds of karma...
And so I forged him a sword,
suffused with special passion...
So, was this warrior able to free himself
from the fate he was burdened with?
Looking back on it now, my skills
had yet to fully mature at that point.
In the end, he cut down each of the men
who had once been his dearest friends.
Using the sword that
I had forged for him.
What of the warrior?
Where is he now?
He is no longer among the living.
Even on his deathbed, the actions that
he took continued to break his heart.
And what about the child?
He raised her with care until
she reached adulthood...
...and she is alive and well to this day.
I see...
But why would the warrior go to
such lengths to protect the child?
The warrior would be signing
his own death warrant...
...by fleeing the country
with the child in tow.
And even if she was the child of a friend,
she was no relation to him.
Couldn't the warrior have simply
refused his friend's request?
Yes, that certainly is a mystery.
It certainly strikes me as odd.
To tell you the truth, by some
coincidence I know of someone...
...who reminds me
a great deal of that warrior.
This person also fled from pursuers
after being suddenly entrusted...
...with the child of a
total stranger one day.
And when the child had been
taken from her at one point...
...she took him back, putting her
own life at risk in the process.
And what is most surprising is that
she didn't kill a single one...
...of the many pursuers who
were trying to take her life.
As for what made this person agree
to take the child of another into her care...
...I cannot even begin to
guess at her motivations.
Perhaps it was just because she
didn't have it in her to turn a blind eye...
...to a helpless life that was
about to flicker and die in front of her.
For that reason, she employed masterful
techniques that would not prove lethal.
That is a most fascinating story.
Out of curiosity,
what became of this person?
It pains me to say it,
but she left this world some days ago.
Oh, I see.
As I listened to your story just now...
...it occured to me that perhaps this
warrior might have been worthy...
...of wielding your ultimate blade.
Forgive me for subjecting you
to such idle talk.
Not at all. It is I who have
detained you for far too long.
We will take our leave now. You have
done us a great service once again.
Was there another customer here
before us, by any chance?
Why do you ask?
Ah, you mean that.
Yes, a spear was left here with me.
I'm surprised that a smith
of your caliber...
...would stoop to working on
a weapon as lowly as a spear.
I work on whatever strikes
my fancy, even spears.
Of that I have no doubt.
Excuse us.
For a moment there, I thought that
my luck had finally run out.
Please feel free to go home.
I have heard both sides
of the story now.
Come again in seven days.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Feelings of Chagum's loved ones...
...drive a certain young star reader
to take action.
Next time, "Shuga Thirsts."
Episode 9
Shuga Thirsts
A fallen one will arrive at an answer.