I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Since coming here,
I have been given the opportunity...
...to enjoy housework
for the first time in my life.
Look.
Have they not come to resemble what
people refer to as "mothers' hands"?
I see that you have no intention
of speaking a harsh word to me.
It was because of my incompetence
that Prince Chagum...
Did you come here so that
you could repent your sins?
To this day, I still believe
that Chagum is alive.
I expect that I appear as a
foolish mother in your eyes.
But I simply cannot believe that...
...that person would die
without completing her promised task.
By "that person," you are referring
to the female bodyguard?
I saw in her eyes an indomitable
strength of will and magical power.
Shuga, if you wish to repay what
you see as an obligation toward me...
...will you go and verify with your
own eyes whether Chagum still lives?
If you do that, I will be able
to live here in contentment.
I once believed that a strength similar
to hers dwelled in your own eyes.
Or was I mistaken in that belief?
Episode 9
Shuga Thirsts
Grandpa! I need some rice pounded!
Huh? Who are you?
Whose kid are you?
What's your problem? Can't you talk?
Who are you kids?
No, who are you?
Is the old man out?
I need him to pound
some rice for me.
Ah, I see. So our water mill
had some customers.
Fine, come on in.
Right.
First, we shall establish a new
steel office which will oversee...
...the production
and distribution of iron.
Only those goods that have met
this office's strict standards...
...will be allowed to carry
the palace crest.
Trade with other countries will also
be conducted through this office.
Part of the profits will, of course,
be disbursed to the craftsmen.
In doing this, I believe we will be able
to maintain the highest level of quality...
...and at the same time keep
the craftsmen's morale high.
Very well, I am convinced.
You have considered every detail.
I will present your plan at
the next council meeting.
You have no objections, I take it?
None, Sire.
Thank you, Majesty.
Incidentally, Father...
I understand that Chagum's
personal effects are being collected?
Yes.
Gakai informs me that you hope to
fully lift the water demon's curse...
...by burning all of these items
in the strictest secrecy.
To my knowledge, however...
...it is proving ever more difficult to ensure
that the entire court holds their silence.
If it is agreeable to Your Majesty...
...perhaps I might be entrusted to
carry out this duty solely on my own?
As you wish. I have no objections.
Do as you see fit.
He has grown to be
an exemplary prince.
After Prince Chagum's death,
he seemed rather melancholy.
Yes.
He appears to be his old self again.
I am certain that is due in no small part
to the efforts of his tutor-governor.
Thank you for your
generous words, Sire.
It looks like the sign of the great drought
will remain for quite some time.
Yes. According to a rumor that
I accidentally overheard recently...
When you were relieved
as tutor-governor...
...did you also forget what time
our evening duties are set to begin?
Thanks to you,
our workload is now heavier.
You're setting a bad example
for the apprentices!
In spite of your zeal for your work...
...you seem to be overlooking
what is truly important.
What do you mean by that?
Is that supposed to be an insult?
And what if it is?
Who does he think he is?
It's not like he knows
any more than we do...
How can they be so optimistic?
They are so singlemindedly
focused on purification...
...that they have forgotten
Prince Chagum's sacrifice.
Stop dawdling. Let's go.
Master Gakai?
What are you doing in my quarters?
What's that you two have in...
Those are...
We are going to lift
the water demon's curse!
What? But we are star readers! That
makes us no better than magic Weavers!
Our orders are to bring all of...
...Prince Chagum's belongings
to Crown Prince Sagum.
To Crown Prince Sagum?
Deliver them to Ichinomiya Palace
tomorrow morning.
Yes, sir.
Wait a moment!
Doing that will accomplish nothing!
Are you trying to comfort yourself by
looking at the late prince's belongings?
You should be ashamed!
Hand them over!
You mustn't!
Why, you...
Please, you must listen to me!
I've had enough of you! Give me that!
Master, let go of me!
I'm so sorry...
Are you injured?
Leave us.
Uh...
Leave us!
I am sorely disappointed in you.
There will be repercussions for this.
Apparently, the master star reader has
ordered him placed under house arrest.
That is to be expected.
However, Master Shuga does not
appear to be the least bit penitent.
I am told that he has voluntarily
relinquished his private quarters...
...and has instead taken up residence
in the star reader apprentices' dormitory.
I presume you have
heard what happened.
Just go about your normal routine.
Master Shuga. Crown Prince Sagum
requests your presence.
The crown prince?
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
I hear detailed accounts of Your Highness'
deeds in every corner of the court.
They are nothing compared to
what I am hearing about you.
Here in Ichinomiya Palace, not a day
goes by in which your name is not spoken.
But it is hard to believe that these
rumors could possibly be about you.
With all due respect, Highness, the matter
regarding the late prince's belongings...
It does not strike me
as something that you would do.
Not a day goes by in which
smoke does not rise...
...from the gardens behind
Ichinomiya Palace.
I respected you from the
bottom of my heart as a man...
...who was a caring older brother first,
and was the first prince second.
However, it seems that
I was wrong about you.
Look.
It happened just inside the forest there.
Chagum had such a keen memory
for facts regarding animals.
That day, his sharp eye spotted a bird
in flight that he had read about in a book.
We remembered the book saying that
this rare bird preyed upon flying frogs...
So we both threw aloft
every rock that we could find.
Perhaps it was unable to bear
the weight of the stones...
It may have been an innocent prank,
but it was a foolish act all the same.
It was Chagum who suggested
that we bring it to the palace...
...and nurse it back to health.
The bird was discovered by Father.
He scolded Chagum harshly, saying that
the bird's feathers were bad for my asthma.
Surely you remember
what you did then.
I remember it as if it were yesterday.
Undaunted by him,
you said the following...
Your Majesty is being overprotective.
On the contrary, perhaps by showing
concern for small, wounded lives...
...and by caring for the animals
and plants of the outside world...
...not only will a sound mind
and body be nurtured...
...but perhaps those qualities vital in
leaders of men will also be cultivated.
Apparently, the mikado was quite
taken aback by what you said.
But I am told that it was this incident
that caused the master star reader...
...to make you the
second tutor-governor.
It is no wonder.
Such was the magnetism and
conviction that you had back then.
As you did just now when you offered
me such frank and sincere criticism.
No one suspects me.
The courteous crown prince
has the complete trust of the court.
Then you did this so that you
could protect his belongings?
Here.
I shall leave them
in your care, Highness.
I no longer have need of them.
I see.
You know, I was always
jealous of Chagum.
How I wish I could have seen
Chagum as mikado...
...and you serving at his side
as master star reader.
Highness...
What I ought to be doing right now...
...is not gazing into the heavens
lamenting the death of the prince.
But rather uncovering why the
sign of the great drought...
...has not disappeared in spite
of the prince's noble sacrifice!
Go on and join those other children.
It's the perfect chance for you
to make some friends, right?
I have no real desire
to play with children...
Oh, just get out there.
Excuse me, what are you doing?
You're kidding, right?
We're racing to see
whose leaf boat is the fastest.
Leaf boats?
You want to race, too?
You do know how to make a boat, right?
Try making one yourself.
Oh, he's made some friends already?
Well, I can't say for sure yet.
Come on, you don't know
how to make a leaf boat?
Uh-oh. Do you think you should have
taught him how to fight first?
Who do you think has the harder job?
...Or a man raising a girl on his own?
Are you talking about Jiguro?
Let me think...
Yes, it's definitely harder
for a man to raise a girl.
The thought of being handed a girl the
same age as him sends chills up my spine.
The difference is that boys will grow up by
themselves even if you leave them alone.
Well, by the time I met you,
you were pretty much a boy anyway.
I suppose I should start making dinner.
Really? Are you sure?
You said it yourself, didn't you?
He'll do just fine on his own.
Look, brother! A flying frog!
What? Where?
See? Over there!
Actually, its official name
is the Nayoro Flying Frog.
Come on, everybody!
Four!
Five!
Six!
Don't!
You mustn't do that!
The frogs are jumping
to try to catch their food!
It is wrong to interfere just
to play some childish game!
What is it with you?
Come on, this isn't
fun any more. Let's go.
Each location's soil samples contain
the normal amount of water...
Are they biting?
What?
Oh, yes.
That is quite a catch you have there.
And look, nothing but big fish!
Yes, thank you for saying so.
What about the number?
Has the number of fish declined?
No, it's no different than the usual.
Um... Is there something
wrong with the fish?
What about the
vegetable and fruit crops?
Has the harvest been good?
Yes, it looks like everyone's
been having a bumper crop.
Thank goodness...
The sign of the great drought is fading.
This means that the prince's death
was not in vain, I suppose.
This one is pretty impressive.
This one is huge, too!
You there, what is it
that you are doing?
I spotted these rare grasses,
and I couldn't help myself.
You can make an effective medicine for
stomachaches with the roots of this plant.
Those are fine tools
that you have there.
Are they all yours?
Yes.
Would you mind if I
took a look at them?
Ah, these graduations
let you measure things...
Would you mind...
What were you measuring
with this stuff?
Is there some reason why
you need to investigate the river?
No, I was investigating something
that will happen in the future.
To determine whether or not there will
be a change in the amount of water.
The amount of water?
Take a look.
Is there something important
about that plant?
No, not the plant.
Look. It's a mantis egg.
A mantis?
This one's just an empty husk now, but
the height at which a mantis lays its eggs...
...can give you a rough idea of how much
water there will be the following year.
For instance, it's said that when eggs
are laid close to the ground like this one...
...there will be hardly
any snow that winter.
Is that true?
Well, that was the case
this year, remember?
It's just an oral tradition among
the Yakoo, but I think it's accurate.
The Yakoo?
Right.
The truth is, I was worried that there
might be a shortage of water soon.
Assuming that what you say is correct...
...the fish in this river are large and fat...
...and the fruit and vegetable
crops are abundant.
If that's the case...
...does that not contradict
what you just said?
Well, maybe not.
Animals gorge on food to fatten up
before they hibernate for the winter, right?
Yes...
Maybe what we're seeing
is something like that.
Maybe all the animals,
and even the plants...
...are preparing themselves to survive a
set of conditions that will be on us soon.
If you look at it that way, everything fits.
This is what you are saying, then?
That within a year, there is a possibility
that this land will be visited by a drought?
What is it?
Well, judging from your appearance,
I think you're from the court.
So why are you out here
investigating something like that?
Hey!
Sir! Will you be needing
the boat or not?
I shall be right there.
Well, I should be taking my leave now.
What about you?
What is your trade?
I'm an herbologist.
If the sign of the great drought
has not disappeared...
...then perhaps Prince Chagum is still
alive somewhere, as the second queen said.
It would seem that I must begin my
investigations again from square one.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Worried about Chagum's decidedly
un-"common" demeanor...
...Balsa decides to
take drastic measures.
Next time, "Soil and Heroes."
Episode 10
Soil and Heroes
Will the dice that Balsa rolls
come up good luck or bad?