I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
What I think doesn't matter.
They lost their home because of me.
Besides, the uproar has mostly died down,
so I don't think there will be any problems.
You think? Well, I'm sure
Tonya's going to be ecstatic.
Really... I know he's
a town boy and all...
...but I never imagined that he'd have such
a hard time getting used to village life.
Compared to him,
Chagum's done an admirable job.
Where's Tonya now?
I promised that I'd find a place for him,
so we're supposed to meet up later.
That's perfect. Take us along with you.
There's something I want
to ask him to do for me.
Some drastic measures
are called for here.
Episode 10
Soil and Heroes
Drastic measures, huh?
As far as I can tell, he seems
to be fitting in well enough.
That's because Chagum isn't the
introverted type, and he's not timid.
The thing is, he's too
clever for his own good.
Also, since he was already
accustomed to isolation...
...he would never complain
even if he was feeling lonely.
But that's not going to help him
live his life here in town, will it?
Unless he becomes a true commoner,
he'll always feel stifled.
You really think so?
In that case, I guess the real issue is
whether Tonya will make a good instructor.
Balsa!
You're really alive!
They said you were alive,
but you really are!
Sorry about everything.
I've put you through a lot of trouble.
I hope you can forgive me.
Don't be like that... Just seeing you two
alive and well makes it all worth it.
What's Saya up to? Is she okay?
Sure, of course!
She can master anything,
so she can get by anywhere.
She's such a hard worker in the village
that they're bringing her marriage offers.
Isn't that right?
I guess they are.
But you're coming back
to town anyway?
Yeah. We still have all the money that
you gave us, so I thought we'd...
In that case, I know you just got here,
but would you mind doing a job for me?
You mean it? Sure, just name it!
I'll do anything!
The thing is...
...I want you to teach this boy
how to be an errand runner.
What do you say?
I'm up for it, but...
Well...
it'll be all right. I'll be watching nearby.
In that case, I guess we'll be okay.
Come on, you don't need to be
so tense. It's not that hard a job.
I don't know...
I just can't seem to get into it.
Hey, I've got it!
I just came up with a great idea.
From now on, let's pretend
that you're my little brother!
That way, if anybody gets suspicious, we
won't have to make up any lame excuses.
So from now on, call me "big brother."
Big brother?
Rep. Big brother, that's me.
Let's start with that.
Delicious heirlooms
fresh off the grill and piping hot!
Heirlooms?
It's a grilled candy that's a mixture of
egg whites, sugar, and pine nut flour.
They're a favourite of the kids
here in Yogi no Shim.
Listen up.
As long as you have these on you,
you can get anything you want around here.
A hundred of these an coins...
equals one Fugal.
Got that?
Okay, we're going to buy a
40-an bag of heirlooms...
...but just with these.
But that is 10 an short.
What can I get you?
I'd like one bag, please.
That'll be 40 an.
That's pretty steep.
If you go to that stand over there,
you can get them for 30.
Really? Where is it?
The food stand in the alley over there.
All right, then. I think I'll
buy mine over there too.
Hey...hold on a minute!
Just give one of mine a try,
and you'll see! They're delicious!
Still... I think I'll go with
the cheaper ones after all.
Wait, wait, wait!
Okay, I'll give you a special discount
just this once! How about 30?
Worked like a charm, I see.
I did not believe that he
would lower the price so easily.
You need to learn how to do
what we just did all by yourself.
Don't worry about it now.
For your first time, you did great!
Good, aren't they?
Now you're an official resident
of Yogi no Shim.
Huh? Where's...
Well, I guess she's
around here some place.
Ready for your next lesson?
Mon In Zen...so exciting
you'll shout yourself hoarse!
Ladies and gentlemen,
place your bets!
What is that?
Mon In Zen. It's what you'd call
a game of chance. Gambling.
It's a game for grown-ups.
Hey, wait a minute...
This might count as
social education too.
Come on, place your bets!
Who will bet a an?
Who will bet a copper Fugal?
Place your bet, and leave it to
the mercy of the gods!
Mon In Zen...so exciting
you'll shout yourself hoarse!
Ladies and gentlemen,
place your bets!
Mon!
In!
The man over there spins
foreign coins that have a white face.
He spins a total of three of them...
...and the object of the game is to bet
how many of them will come up heads.
If it's one, it's Mon.
If it's two, that's In.
If all three come up white, that's Zen,
and you get back twice what you bet.
But if three blacks come up...
...that's called "house takes all"
and the house wins everything.
All right, the final coin
is about to be spun!
Are there any other bets?
My, this young man is a big better!
We have a last-minute bet on Zen!
A perfect place to close the betting!
The time for speculation is over!
Whether it's heads or tails...
it's up to your prayers!
Pray that the coins
will come your way!
Stuff like this doesn't really make sense
unless you try it for yourself.
Okay, let's see a Zen!
Yes! Yes!
Two whites! In!
Anyway, that's how the game works...
Come on, place your bets!
Who will bet a an?
Who will bet a copper Fugal?
In this game, does one have to bet
before the third coin is spun?
No, you're allowed to place your bet
until the first coin lands...
...but it's not as exciting
if you wait that long, you know?
You gotta be ready to bet
before he spins the first coin.
Otherwise, you're never Donna win.
Oh, I'm such a moron!
Do you know how many lunches I could've
bought from Yogi's with that Fugal?
Crap! I manna get it back!
You were better off losing.
What're you talking about?
Winning is always better!
That is true enough,
but you could not have won.
It seemed like the coin spinner could make
the coins come up any way he wanted.
Come on, how could he
possibly do that?
Wait, how could you possibly know that the
first time you saw the game being played?
I do not know how I know.
I just know.
Are you serious?
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
One white! Mon!
Wow, you're right!
See? If this goes on, these people
will lose all of their money.
Do you see that large carpenter
sitting there?
He will most likely lose
in the next round as well.
The old woman over there is
winning for the time being...
...but I suspect that she
will be their next target.
What makes you say that?
Because she will bet
more than one Fugal.
FM-More than one...
When one bets using an coins...
...losing does not seem so bad.
But anyone who loses a Fugal would
definitely want to win it back, right?
That's for sure...
But to win back one Iugal, one would
have to win ten bets of 10 han.
Even betting 50 han, one would still have
to win twice to recover that Iugal, see?
With that in mind, the impulse is not to
bet on Mon or Jin, whose odds are 3-in-8...
...but rather to bet on Zen's
double return in spite of its 1-in-8 odds.
But that person is manipulating
the outcome of the final throw...
...making it so that they
make a profit in the end.
That is also why Zen comes up
so often when no one has bet on it.
H-Hey, wait just a minute!
If they can really do that, wouldn't that
make this... a rigged game?
But for those men, it is also their livelihood,
so it can't really be helped.
Well, no, but...
Also, the majority of the people here
seem to be enjoying the gambling.
If one's objective were to earn money,
it would be insanity to play such games.
It is difficult to spot individually because
of the difference in their wins and losses.
But seen as a house-versus-player game,
even if the house does not cheat...
...the odds are so heavily stacked against
these people that they cannot win.
Goodness, I lost.
If you'd kept winning, we would've been
driven out of business by one little old lady.
Looks like luck is still on our side.
I'll win for sure next time, just you wait!
Come on, place your bets!
I'm going over there.
I can't let this go.
Who do you think you are,
you big, fat cheat?
You're playing dirty!
Run the game fair and square!
What are we going to do with that boy?
You're slandering our good name.
I can understand that you're angry
because you lost all your money...
...but if you're penniless,
you'd better leave.
Yeah, beat it!
It's no use. Let's go.
I hoped that I could at least
keep them from losing all their money...
...but I guess it's beyond me.
Wait a moment.
I thought that you wanted to
recover your money, Toya.
I played with fire, and I got burned.
It's okay. Let's go.
Let's stop them.
If you want to help these people,
I will do it for you.
Hey! Chagum!
This is exactly why commoners
are looked down upon as fools.
They delude themselves
into thinking that a game is fair...
...even when that game
is rigged against them.
Truly, what a bunch of fools!
Do you not see?
This man can make the coins
come up whichever way he wants.
If you continue playing,
you will be the first to lose.
Then you will lose, ma'am.
And then you, miss.
They are simply letting you
win for the time being.
But before you know it,
your pockets will be empty.
You cannot see through such
a simple scam, and that is why...
...you will always remain
the ignorant masses.
Who does this kid think he is?
Honestly! Don't talk like
you know everything, boy.
He's just jealous of us. It's because
his big brother lost his money.
You better hurry home, boy.
Or you'll get into trouble
with your mama.
Wait, that's me!
You have guts, little man.
Seeing as how you're so sure
of what you say...
...I assume you can prove that this man
can control what side comes up?
Balsa...
Very well. I shall prove it to you.
What are you saying?
You can't prove it!
Balsa isn't around, either!
C'mon, let's go!
It is all right. Leave this to me.
You ready, big brother?
Y-Yeah!
One white... Mon.
I have won the argument, I take it?
That was just one round.
Wait a minute.
I'll bet for the boy.
That okay with you?
There it is! A double return!
We did it!
He can tell how they'll land?
Keep playing.
I want in too!
We should bet on Jin, right?
No. That will not work.
Do not bet on anything.
What do you mean?
No one can win this round.
Three black! House takes all!
Not betting on the last one
was a smart move.
Yes, but the money you bet
on the first throws is...
That's all right. You have to tell us.
How do you know?
I'm dying to know! Please, tell me!
This man can control the outcome of
the first two coins using the third coin.
When he throws the third coin...
...one can tell the outcome
by looking at this man's hand.
When he grips his sash with
the thumb on top, it signals Mon.
When he grips it with the thumb
tucked into the sash, that signals Jin.
When he clenches his fist, that is
the signal for the roller to produce Zen.
Now I get it... That's unacceptable.
Here in Yogo,
we call that a fixed game.
I want my money back!
What are you trying to pull?
You damned con artists!
I do understand that you
are running a business here.
But these people are
enjoying your game.
From now on, please run your games
according to official guidelines.
Right, big brother?
Yeah, that's right.
Wait a minute.
How about a one-on-one match?
After what you've done, we can't
show our faces around here again.
So let's play an
all-or-nothing round with no tricks.
I'll throw the coins myself.
If you win, I'll return all of the money
that we got from these people today.
But if I win, I walk away with
that necklace of yours.
No, don't do it!
You can't bet the necklace!
You got that from your...
I accept.
Here we go.
He won! He won!
That was awesome!
He did it, he did it!
He did it!
H-Hey, I'm not the one
you should be picking up!
C'mon, brother! Wait for me!
Big brother!
You're the big brother, you fool!
Hey! Come on, mister! Put me down!
Well, that was a surprise...
I thought I was waking a sleeping child...
...but I might have aroused something
more formidable than I thought.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Toya has disappeared.
Saya has lost consciousness.
And then Tanda...
Next time, "Flower Wine for Tanda."
Episode 11
Flower Wine for Tanda
May my prayers reach the border
between Nayug and Sag...