I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
It doesn't matter how
much money I have.
Without her, it doesn't mean a thing!
Episode 11
Flower Wine for Tanda
Would you mind telling me again
how she seemed yesterday?
It was about this time yesterday.
She just collapsed all of a sudden.
And what about after she collapsed?
There was no fever, and since it
looked like she was just sleeping...
...I assumed that the flower wine had
gone to her head, so I put her to bed.
Flower wine?
But why would she
be drinking flower wine?
Well, it was to celebrate
a happy occasion.
May I come in?
Chagum? Did you
come here by yourself?
Yes, I was with Balsa till
just before I reached the village.
Balsa said she was going to look
for Toya and went back to town.
What happened to Saya?
Is she ill?
No, but judging from the
examination I gave her a while ago...
...it's almost as if her
soul has left her body.
Do you mean one of those out-of-body
experiences one hears about?
Yes. It's not unusual for something
to trigger the soul to leave the body.
Like when you're dozing off
and you suddenly jerk awake...
...because it feels like you're falling?
That sensation is the moment
that your soul leaves your body.
Normally, though, the soul hurries
straight back to the body, and you wake up.
We do not need
to worry about Saya then?
This is it, huh?
This is the house that
Tanda rented for them.
If he isn't here,
that must mean he's...
I don't feel like doing
anything at all any more...
Don't feel like doing what?
Balsa!
Such a fine house you're renting...
Why would you abandon it?
There's no point in living
in that house all by myself.
Thank you for coming
all the way out here today.
Come, we can discuss
the particulars while we eat.
Are you sure?
In that case...
You have done such
a fine job raising Saya...
...even though she's
not your sister by blood.
Well, I guess she's more like
a daughter than a sister to me.
I don't want to pat myself on the back,
but you won't find a better girl than Saya!
I'm quite sure she is.
That being the case, if her
happiness is your main concern...
...I strongly suggest
that you accept this offer.
You're absolutely right, of course.
The thing is, Saya's still such a child.
Not at all, Saya is already
a fine young woman.
The match I have suggested
for her is also a fine young man.
And his family is above reproach.
I believe that there is
no finer match to be found.
Please accept this sum
as her betrothal gift money.
Any big brother would
want his sister to be happy...
But what I think doesn't matter.
Saya hasn't agreed, so I can't possibly...
Oh, if that is your concern,
do not worry.
I have already received
a favorable response from Saya.
Thank you for taking
such good care of me.
I see.
It sounds like Saya's
collapse and that meeting...
...have some sort of link.
Saya collapsed?
I don't know the details,
but that's why I came here to get you.
Ah, so that's what happened.
A marriage was being
arranged for Saya.
Yes, with the son of the rice merchant
we always do business with.
Arranged marriages are something
to be happy about, aren't they?
Yes, but something terrible
might have happened...
...and her soul is refusing to
return to her body because of it.
Something terrible?
How did Saya seem
at the marriage meeting?
Was there anything
that struck you as odd?
Well, she did seem
to be brooding a bit.
Saya!
Why is this happening?
Why is this happening to Saya!
This is why I was against it!
But I was told that you
gave your blessing right away.
It was such a good match that you
just charmed them into it, didn't you?
You lied... How could
you do that to us?
I'm sorry, Saya. If I'd only
been clear in turning her down...
Now that we know what
caused her condition...
...won't Saya's soul return if we
tell her that the marriage is off?
It should, but she can't seem
to hear us the way she is now.
The only way to help her is
to perform a soul-summoning.
A soul-summoning?
Saya's soul has probably gone to
the other world, so I'll send my own...
...and bring hers back with me.
Are you really capable of
doing something of that scale?
My mentor did teach me how to do it.
In any case, I'd like
to prepare for the spell.
I'll have to ask everyone
to go into the next room.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Ready...
I'm going to start now.
Make sure that no one
comes into this area.
Now then, if you two could
join the others in the next room...
You want me to go too?
Didn't Torogai forbid you from
ever performing a soul-summoning?
If you were about
to jump into a well...
...I'd feel confident that
I could pull you up.
But you can't exactly
tie a rope to a soul.
I know the risks.
But since Torogai isn't here,
I have to do it myself.
Well, you have a point...
Don't worry. I'll make sure
I summon Saya's soul back to us.
If things go wrong,
and I don't make it back...
...I'll be watching over you at night.
I'll be keeping an eye
on you here. Do your best.
All right.
Soul, spread your wings...
Become like a bird
soaring through the sky...
What on earth?
So it didn't work?
Looks like you did it.
It seems that my soul
has left my body.
That's...
Saya?
Can you hear me, Saya?
Tanda?
What are you doing here?
I'm here to bring you back.
Everyone's worried about you.
I didn't want to agree
to the marriage.
But I just couldn't say no.
It's all right.
Don't worry about that any more.
But she said that Toya would surely
be punished if I didn't get married.
Because I'm not really his sister...
So I lied to Toya about
wanting to get married.
So that's what happened.
But you don't have to worry.
There are no grounds
to punish Toya for anything.
Really?
Really. And Toya is
sitting in the next room.
He was so worried about you
that he came storming in here.
But I can't go back... I think I died.
Don't worry, you aren't dead.
But I...
Go on.
How's it coming?
I think it's working.
Toya!
Saya...
Saya!
Toya!
Please take her to the next room
and give her some hot water to drink.
She hasn't had anything to eat
or drink for a day and a half.
Good idea.
So she made it back?
Tanda hasn't returned yet?
His curiosity always
gets the better of him.
He must be lingering on his
way back from the other world.
You should join the others
and get something to eat too.
I'll keep an eye on Tanda.
You can't find your
way back, can you?
I'm at my wits' end...
I don't know how to come back.
Do you remember what
I said to you two years ago...
...when you came back
all covered in blood?
If you have to take one life
to save another, what's the point?
I asked if you were killing more
than you were saving, didn't I?
I didn't really mean to
say that to you, but I...
I stormed out of your
place two years ago...
...but looking back on it now,
I think I was just being stubborn.
But it was your words that kept me
from killing a single person since then.
Thank you.
No, I'm the one
who should apologize.
I finally understand now...
How anxious you were back then.
How saving the lives of others
chips away at your own life, bit by bit.
I'm sorry for that, Balsa.
Damn it, what am I doing!
Has the sun come up already?
This is Nayug?
That's Sagu's moon...
So that means...
But what an incredible world...
So at this moment, I'm literally on
the border between Nayug and Sagu?
Tanda still hasn't woken up?
Chagum, are those
rice cakes for me?
I really have to
come up with something...
It can...
It travels back and forth
between Nayug and Sagu?
But how?
Come to think of it...
Saya's out-of-body experience was
triggered by drinking that flower wine.
Damn! That's it!
Somehow, I've got to...
But how can I
make them understand?
The Nyunga Ro Im egg?
I'm being pulled straight into
Nayug because of the egg then?
If this egg actually straddles the
border of Nayug and Sagu, then I can...
What's wrong?
Tanda?
Chagum!
We have to give Tanda
some of that flower wine!
It was the nectar of
those flowers in the wine...
...that caused Saya's
soul to leave her body!
Couldn't you have done
that a little more gently?
I have to admit, I didn't see it at all...
So, Saya is in love with Toya.
Did you notice anything?
No. But in hindsight,
I suppose all the signs were there.
What?
There's a double moon tonight.
You know, that second
one was Nayug's sun.
They say that Sagu and Nayug are
drawn to each other during the full moon.
It must be true.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
The Founding Day Festival is held in
farm villages on the summer solstice...
Next Time
To defend his father's honor,
Chagum challenges a foreign boy.
Next time,
"The Summer Solstice Festival."
Episode 12
The Summer Solstice Festival
This first act of defiance
forges lasting bonds.