I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
She's alive...
Episode 13
Neither Human nor Tiger
Put the unburned firewood
next to the stove.
All right.
Hey! Lady!
A warrior told me
to give this letter to you!
A warrior?
Good morning.
Hey. You were really
amazing yesterday!
Um, you think so? It was just luck.
Listen, who taught you that move?
Don't tell me it was...
What did the letter say?
Is it a challenge from somebody
who saw the match last night?
Something like that.
Chagum! Pack your
things right away.
Something's come up,
and we have to leave.
Are you going to be all right?
I didn't sense anyone following us.
That's not what I meant.
What I'm saying is that...
...judging by his choice of words, it
doesn't sound like you can reason with him.
I agree. Looks like we were
spotted by the wrong person.
Who is he, anyway?
Who's this warrior named Karbo?
I guess you could
call him a business rival.
When I rescued a client
from slavers three years ago...
...he was a bodyguard
working for the other side.
Can't you lay low here with Chagum?
I want to keep living at the
water mill until Torogai returns.
But if I don't meet him,
he's going to expose me to the court...
...so I have no choice.
If we get spotted here,
it will all have been for nothing.
I can't let someone who
knows my identity run loose.
He might have realized
that Chagum is alive too.
I gave my word that
I wouldn't take another life.
I'll find a way to avoid killing him.
Look after Chagum.
This is all because
I went to the festival...
Don't worry about it. This was
bound to happen sooner or later.
I'm sure that Balsa
realizes that too.
So, I guess I wasn't
seeing things when I saw...
...a dead woman in
a Iucha match last night.
What happened to
your Yogo sword?
I gave it up.
Ever since our last meeting...
...I promised myself that
I was going to kill you using this.
I'm sorry, but you'll have
to forget that you saw me.
I mean to make you
pay for humiliating me!
Like it or not,
you are going to fight me.
I've been waiting a long time
for this day to arrive.
All I could think about was killing you,
so I even took part in that manhunt.
Granted, you did ambush me...
...but why did you leave me dishonored
and defeated without finishing me off?
Who's to say?
That boy who was with you.
He's the second prince, isn't he?
Good, that's the look
I wanted to see.
Tomorrow morning, be at
the Tonan highway barrier.
You don't know when
to give up, do you? I...
Whether or not you come to
the barrier is entirely your choice.
But know that I will follow the first traveler
who leaves the barrier after sunrise...
...and kill him.
And I will do this every morning
until you do decide to show up.
The only way to stop me
is for you to kill me yourself.
The humiliation of
a sword wielded for oneself...
...being defeated by a sword
wielded in the service of another...
I will settle the past by killing you.
If I don't, my spirit will never
be able to put this behind me...
...no matter how much
I train and discipline myself.
I am grateful to you for being alive.
Hey! W-What's gotten into you!
Whoa! Whoa, now!
S-Sensei!
Thank you so much.
I'm not used to handling horses...
It couldn't be helped. A horse gone
wild can't be reined in by a novice.
Sensei! I'm so sorry!
Are you all right?
Yes...
Normally, she's such a docile horse...
Thank you for helping us.
That's strange, why'd you
go wild all of a sudden?
Come on, there's nothing out there.
You hired a stone shooter, I see.
Just like the last time...
I-I think we should go.
She's been following us
ever since the gate...
Most likely because this is
the only road leading south.
It bothers me that her short spear is just
like the one the warrior on that rock had.
Let's take a break there then.
And where might
you be traveling to?
How about yourselves?
Our plan is to go to a fishing village
at the southern tip of the mainland.
What a coincidence.
What in the world!
Who would do something like this?
Why don't you come
closer to the fire?
Don't worry about me.
I'm used to the cold.
You mentioned that you are
also traveling to the fishing village.
Might I ask what takes you there?
Just an errand.
Ah, I see.
As for me, I have been hired to teach
the children there how to read and write.
Oh, you're a teacher?
That's a fine profession.
You seem to be
from another country.
Yes. That's right.
And what sort of work do you do?
I am no expert on the subject
of swords and spears...
...but you wouldn't happen to be
a Kanbal warrior, would you?
Warrior makes it sound
more glamorous than it really is.
I'm just a bodyguard, nothing more.
A female bodyguard?
That must be a difficult line of work.
I suppose.
You say you are a bodyguard,
but a warrior is a warrior.
That being the case,
do you know the Yogo tale called...
..."The Warrior who
Became a Tiger"?
No, I don't.
It's a fable about a warrior
who devoted his entire life...
...to training to increase
his skill with his sword.
So obsessed was
this warrior with power...
...that in hopes of
becoming as strong as a tiger...
...he took to fighting
while clad in a tiger's hide.
The warrior's plan worked...
...and in due time, there
were no more enemies to fight.
But one day, he realized that he had,
in fact, turned into a real tiger.
And then what?
And then the warrior,
who had lost the ability to speak...
...eventually lost
his family and friends...
...and lived out his days
alone in a bamboo grove.
You'll have to forgive me, but
even an untrained eye such as mine...
...can detect an air of
menace coming from you.
That is why I told you that story.
You can, can you? I suppose
I still need some more training.
If you'll excuse me...
I knew you could do it, Sensei!
You managed to send that dreadful
warrior away without angering her!
You misunderstand. I didn't
tell her that story to drive her away.
On the contrary, I was curious about
why she has such a thirst for blood...
...and had hoped to ask her why.
You're a strange one, Sensei.
I've been scared to death of that
woman ever since this afternoon.
This should keep the rain off.
A stone shooter and dead rats...
And now his plan is
to keep me from sleeping, huh?
You're planning to come after me using
exactly the same tactics I used on you...
Apparently, I have no choice
but to play along with him.
Nothing fazes this lady, does it?
My shots are grazing her cheek,
but she hasn't so much as blinked.
Shall I fire one
right into her forehead?
Do only as you're told.
Who is she, anyway?
You don't need to know.
Suffice it to say that she's the
only opponent I've ever failed to kill.
I wouldn't have this any other way.
Keep her awake by firing stones
at her at random intervals.
If she moves, move with her.
Keep it up all night.
If she goes inside the hut,
fire your stones into the roof or walls.
But if she attacks you,
you're to clear out right away.
Under no circumstances
are you to kill her. Is that clear?
Yes, sir!
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Well, it was raining hard,
so I guess she went on ahead.
I see that it's stopped raining.
Yes.
And it looks like that
woman has left too.
I think we can relax now.
I'm sorry, but I'll be
accompanying you again today.
Where did you sleep last night?
I didn't.
Then you should have
just gone on ahead!
Why did you wait around for us?
There's something creepy about you!
There's no need
to take that tone of voice.
But she's...
I don't mind.
But there's a very good reason
why I have to stay close to you two.
That's ridiculous.
We don't want you around!
I know it's against the rules for the
packhorse driver to ride with the client...
...but please bear with me until
we can get away from this woman!
Wait! If you leave my side, you'll...
Are you all right?
Stay away!
He leaves me no choice...
The truth is, I've gotten
you two involved in my affairs...
When you left the barrier gate, you
saw a warrior standing on a rock, right?
If I had turned back,
he was going to kill one of you.
This man challenged me
to a sword fight, you see.
When I refused...
...he said he would kill the first person
to pass through the gate each day.
Then if you had not been there...
Either you or your packhorse driver
would have been killed.
I-I don't believe this!
The problem is, for various reasons,
I've sworn to never take another life.
I had hoped to find a way
to avoid fighting him...
...while also keeping him from
involving innocent bystanders.
But it looks like he isn't
going to listen to reason.
Are you out of your mind?
I don't care what your reasons are!
If you don't want to fight,
go let him kill you!
Just leave other people out of it!
I agree. But I can't afford
to be killed just yet.
Karbo! I know you're
out there listening!
Just as you did to me, I was
going to attack after trailing you...
...for three days and
nights with no sleep.
But if this is the way
you want it, I'll oblige you.
I'm going to unburden myself
right here and now!
Get going! He doesn't have
any more use for you two.
Come on!
Those two are my shooter's reward.
Enough is enough!
I'm the one you're fighting!
Pay attention to nothing but me!
I guess I have no choice
but to become a tiger...
That's more like it!
Now you'll be worth killing!
Wait! Wait a minute!
You two are my reward!
I won't force you
to strip down or anything.
Put down all your money and go!
You too!
I got him...
Come on, Sensei,
let's get out of here.
Not yet, we have to
stop that woman.
What are you talking about?
We should just let
those two kill each other!
Dragging us into their mess
when we had nothing to with it...
Damn it!
Nothing to do with it?
Are you so sure about that?
That woman secretly acted as
our bodyguard and kept us safe.
Come on! it's not
like we asked her to...
We mustn't allow her
to turn into a tiger!
Sensei!
Let me tell you the reason
why I didn't kill you that day.
I had sworn to save the same
number of lives that I had taken.
But by the time I fought you,
I had already realized that all lives...
...weren't of equal value.
That's why I was sick of killing
insignificant scum like you...
...every time I saved
someone else's life.
Insignificant scum?
But there's still something that
I need to see through to the end!
And whoever gets in my way...
Who are you calling
insignificant scum?
How dare you...
How dare you call me insignificant!
Sensei, please!
Sensei!
You mustn't!
You mustn't kill that man!
What have you done...
Why did you...
Shut your mouth! I'm a tiger!
Don't come near me
or I'll rip you apart!
I'm insignificant...
Sensei, what in the world
just happened here?
I have no idea. I could have sworn
that she struck this man down.
This whole time,
I was beneath her notice...
Please! Go call her back!
She thinks that she killed this man!
But the truth is she didn't!
If we don't tell her that
he's still alive, she's going to...
I-I'm on my way!
You there. Do you know
what that woman's name is?
I don't know.
No, I've forgotten it...
Hey!
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
With no regard to their own safety,
two sages make discoveries.
One, a long-buried history.
The other, a hidden conspiracy.
Next time,
"The Knot."
Episode 14
The Knot
Look around you! What the
world needs now is this truth!