I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
With the first month of the new year,
you will finally come of age...
...and you will be permitted to wear
a sword within the imperial court.
You are aware of this, I take it?
I am.
As your father, I intend to
bestow a sword upon you today.
Sagum...
May you wear it in good health.
Thank you, Father.
Episode 15
Untimely Death
"The sign of the great drought..."
"...which appears once
every hundred years..."
"...is a natural consequence of the
aged Nyunga Ro Im approaching death."
Natural consequence?
If that is true, then perhaps we
cannot determine if the prince is alive...
...using only the sign of
the great drought as a guide.
Teacher, you're not a young woman
any more. You shouldn't push yourself.
None of your cheek, youngster.
There are times when you can't get
to the truth unless you push yourself.
I have a craving for yamabime.
Boy. Fetch me some yamabime
from the mountains out back.
Yamabime?
What, you don't even
know what yamabime are?
They're a purple fruit with
a clean split down the middle.
Go onto any mountain and you'll
find them hanging from trees all over!
Hurry up and fetch me some!
Go on by yourself.
You'll find some right away
once you reach the mountains.
All right.
That boy is going to die.
What are you talking about?
I thought you said that the egg
wouldn't harm its guardian.
The egg won't.
There's something that you
haven't told us yet, isn't there?
I couldn't say anything
with the boy sitting there.
Apparently, something called "Rarunga"
is going to come here from Nayug.
And what's that?
Unfortunately, I wasn't able
to learn anything specific...
...but the Yona Ro Gai
called it an egg-eater.
I don't even know if
it's a living creature.
Is there a chance that it
will attack him right now?
Can't we just hide Chagum
somewhere until the egg hatches?
That won't do any good.
Apparently, it can't hatch
unless it's taken to...
...something called
the Land of Feasting.
Land of Feasting?
Where is that?
I don't know that, either.
This must be it...
On the other hand,
I did learn when the egg will hatch.
They say it'll be on
Sagu's spring day of equality.
Spring day of equality?
The vernal equinox, most likely.
That's the day when day
and night are the same length.
They said that on that day, the boy
himself will explain everything to us.
Until then, the boy will be safe.
The egg-eater probably won't
turn up until sometime around then.
Sitting around here talking
about it isn't going to help matters.
Let's start by finding out
who or what this Rarunga is.
Yes, but I can't go back to the Knot.
Let's just hope that there's still
something for us to go on out there...
Well, well!
You found some big ones.
They're awfully light
for something so big.
These are plump and ripe!
Back when I was a young girl...
...the storytelling hag of the village
often sent me out to pick these for her.
Mistress, that's it!
A Yakoo storyteller
might know something.
All the Yakoo around here have pretty
much assimilated into Yogoan culture.
I doubt that the oral histories they tell
have been handed down accurately.
What about Toumi village?
The old oral histories
might have survived...
...out in the village
my grandfather moved to.
True, it might be worth going
out to that godforsaken village.
It's better than sitting
around doing nothing.
Are we going somewhere?
Yes, on a journey to
get some information.
A journey? That sounds like
something to look forward to.
I guess you'll go check it out, then.
We'll stop by home first to
make the necessary preparations.
I'll go with you, then.
I want to pick up
some medicinal herbs.
"And then, mammatus clouds appeared
to allow the mother water spirit..."
"...to bestow her final blessing
upon the egg, her child."
"And then, mammatus clouds appeared
to allow the mother water spirit..."
"...to bestow her final blessing
upon the egg, her child"?
"Exactly as described in Yakooan oral
tradition, on the last day of summer..."
"...clouds shaped like breasts
appeared directly above the village..."
"...where the guardian of the
spirit lived, blotting out the sky."
"Almost as if the earth
was swallowing them..."
"...every cloud in the sky was drawn
to a single point on the ground..."
"...after which a localized
downpour began to fall."
This is it! If I can
observe these clouds...
...it will be the proof I need
that Prince Chagum is alive!
What day is today?
Master Shuga?
Is everything all right?
The master star reader
still has the key?
Yes.
I see...
It sounds as if you have
uncovered something important.
I must get out of here
at once to verify something.
Very well, sir.
We will try to find a way...
Hurry!
Our apologies, sir!
Hey!
I am sorry...
You have our deepest
apologies, Master.
How dare you treat the master
star reader with such disrespect!
Has the heat gone to your head?
Such a lack of discipline!
That's enough.
Hurry back to your station.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Why have you entered
these chambers?
I have no idea what you
are referring to, Master.
I take it that you realize the consequences
of entering here without permission.
A pity. In your ten years of service...
...you have never once committed an
offense. I never expected to lose you.
Come with me.
Become empty vessels.
I am sorry. This is all my fault.
We wish for nothing more than
Prince Chagum's safe return.
I am sure that my
comrade has no regrets.
Forgive me.
Your Highness.
The sword the mikado gave you is...
...a bit different than
the style you prefer, isn't it?
The success of a gift is determined by
the attention given to it by the recipient.
What is important is the sentiment
of the giver and recipient.
I see...
The day that signals summer's end...
If that is today, this very day, then...
Nothing...
The prince is alive!
Not only is he alive,
he is right under our noses!
Right here in Kosenkyo!
What a downpour...
It has been a long time since
you were here last, Shuga.
How did you know it was me?
One's senses are always heightened
when one is pressed for time.
How are you feeling,
Your Highness?
It must be because I've been
so focused. I am feeling well.
Does something trouble you, then?
Perhaps my spirit is
somewhat exhausted.
Your Highness...
Playing the role of Crown Prince
Sagum has taken its toll.
With some effort,
I have managed to endure...
...but it now takes every
ounce of my strength.
Your Highness, perhaps you might
delegate some of your duties to others...
...and lessen the
burden placed on you.
If there were a few people
who were truly able to support me...
...that might be possible.
To make matters worse,
I lack a certain crucial quality.
The divine grace to captivate
people's hearts and not let go.
I might use my rank to
sway people to action...
...but it is rather difficult
to sway their hearts as well.
It was Chagum who had this quality.
He had the innate
ability to charm others.
Your Highness,
Prince Chagum is...
Yes, you are right.
Chagum is no longer with us.
But it is because he is gone that I am
able to keep going without breaking.
I will do his share, as well.
I am sorry. I did not mean
to bore you with trivialities.
Not at all, Highness.
If speaking with me lifts your spirits,
I shall come whenever you wish.
You will? I do feel
somewhat better now.
Shuga, I hope you will
continue to be a good friend to me.
Of course, Your Highness.
Now then, what is it that
you wished to discuss?
My apologies, Your Highness.
I should have exercised better judgement.
I will call upon you another time.
I see.
Could you lend the use of
a horse for three days or so?
Yes, but, well...
This is the first time a star reader
has ever borrowed a horse...
You needn't worry.
I come from a family of fishermen.
I've ridden my share of horses.
Chagum, that's quite
a tan you have there.
It is?
You know, I think his skin's
darker than it used to be.
You look a little more
muscular now too.
I think you're right.
Come to think of it, I haven't had
any strange dreams lately, either.
It feels like a huge weight has
been lifted from my shoulders.
When I think about how
I'm free to live my life...
...as I see fit from
now on, I get excited.
Is there something
that you want to do?
I'd like to do something
to help other people...
...and also learn about
things that interest me.
You have the
temperament of a scholar...
...so maybe you should become a
field scholar and teach the local children.
In that case, maybe I'll buy him a writing
desk so that he can read and write.
What we learned...
Are you going to tell Chagum?
Eventually, I'll probably have
no choice but to tell him.
But at the moment,
we don't know anything for sure.
Oh, right. Take this.
It's a map to Toumi village.
If I uncover proof that
Prince Chagum is still alive...
...and report my findings
to the master star reader...
...everything will work out!
Prince Sagum.
This correspondence
has just arrived.
Gakai, I find myself
a bit exhausted...
Your Highness?
You have taught me
a great many things.
I am grateful to you.
You are too kind, Your Highness.
From now on, I want you to
cooperate with Shuga as a star reader...
...and make the palace
a better place.
I will.
Gakai.
Your Highness?
Will you release
that bird into the sky?
Are you sure, Your Highness?
Yes. I can no longer give it
the attention it deserves.
Indeed. Considering all your duties
as crown prince, perhaps it is time.
Go on, fly away!
His Highness commands you to fly.
Go on! Fly, I say!
Go on... Shoo!
It is flying strongly, Your Highness.
Surely the result of the
tender care you lavished upon it.
Farewell...
Forgive me, Chagum...
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Shuga, who has been given full command
over the search for Chagum...
...once again sets the Hunters
loose upon Ogi no Shimo.
Next time,
"With All one's Heart."
Episode 16
With All One's Heart
The unforgettable summer
is about to come to an end.