I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Hello!
What's this?
Balsa isn't home?
It's not like I can just leave
all this here and go, either...
She's out?
Looks that way.
Let's talk to the neighbours and get a
description of the people who live there.
Right.
It's so tranquil around here...
Episode 17
The Water Mill Burns
That's...
The prince is walking about
on his own, buying sweets?
Prince Chagum.
Shuga?
I'd like to see that
children's-size karru too.
Here you are!
Your Highness...
to find you in such a state...
There are too many people here.
This way, please.
Thank goodness you are safe.
You have suffered
hardship for a long time.
But those days of
deprivation are now over.
Meeting you here is surely
a sign from the heavens.
I will escort you back to
the palace immediately.
But no, you see...I...
You needn't worry, Your Highness.
I have already determined
what sort of being possesses you.
It is not something that taints you.
It is a benevolent spirit, one
which blesses our lands with water.
I have informed the mikado
of my findings, as well.
So I assure you, there is no longer
anyone who wishes you harm...
That's quite a
self-serving speech there.
Ah, you must be Balsa.
First you send assassins to kill him,
and then the instant...
...circumstances change, you
suddenly want to bring him home.
Don't you think you're
being a bit too selfish?
You don't understand, Balsa.
This man is...
True, you have my deepest gratitude
for protecting the prince thus far.
However, he no longer
requires your protection.
You will be exonerated of any crimes
and will be given a suitable reward.
I can see you have
the wrong idea about me.
I haven't been protecting this boy
with the aim of making money.
It's because his mother asked me to
keep him safe for the rest of his life.
The only one who can terminate
our agreement is the second queen.
In that case, I shall terminate it
in the second queen's stead.
That's not good enough.
After sharing life's joys and sorrows for
so long, your attachment is no surprise.
But we can no longer afford to
be swayed by such sentiments.
I must ask you to know your place
and back down without an argument.
I'm sorry, but even if the
second queen were to come for him...
...I couldn't do as you ask.
What?
I don't know how much you've learned
about what's possessing the boy...
...but there are compelling reasons
why I can't send him back to the palace.
What is it that you have uncovered?
Let's go, Chagum.
Your Highness!
Prince Sagum has passed away.
What are you talking about?
His duties as crown prince were
apparently too great a burden.
He passed away some
days ago as if falling asleep.
You're lying.
No, Your Highness, this is no lie.
Spear-wielder, you
see how things stand.
If His Highness does not return,
the palace will be thrown into turmoil.
I cannot humor you and your
so-called reasons at this time.
Leave us. A messenger
will eventually be sent for you.
I can't do that.
If you insist on taking the prince,
you'll have to kill me first.
Otherwise, I will send
a military force after you.
We have already
located your hideout.
Prince Chagum!
Everyone is eagerly
awaiting your return!
I shall serve you to the best
of my abilities, so please!
Chagum, I'll explain
everything on the road.
Wait, Balsa! My brother is...
Come on!
Shuga!
Balsa and the others
sure are taking forever...
I guess there's no choice.
Sometimes my own
thoughtfulness amazes me!
He put down the goods and left?
Yeah.
So, how about you?
Did you learn anything?
It seems that a woman and
child have been living there.
Let's check out the hut.
They're going to Toumi village?
Hey, that's... That's the chief!
From the descriptions we've heard...
...there's a strong possibility that it's
the spear-wielder and Prince Chagum.
What do you want to do?
What did they just say?
It looks like they're out, all right.
All right, I'll keep watch here.
You report back to the commander.
Get the word out to Taga
and Sune on your way back.
Understood.
It can't be...
Chief...
Looks like I've blundered again!
What took you so long?
What's the matter?
Did something happen?
We ran into someone
from the palace.
So, what happened?
He wasn't a warrior, so we
managed to give him the slip.
We can expect pursuit soon, though.
Let's head straight for Toumi village.
But what about the supplies?
It's only a three-day journey.
We'll manage.
I guess we'll have to.
What's the matter, Chagum?
The man we ran into seemed
to be a close acquaintance.
And we heard from him
that Chagum's older brother...
...the first prince,
just passed away...
But that means...
I know, but we have more important
things to worry about right now.
We have no choice.
More important things? What
could possibly be more important?
My brother is dead!
I said that I would
explain later, didn't I?
For now, hold your tongue
and go on ahead with Tanda.
What about you?
I left the map to
Toumi village in the hut.
I'm sure we'll be able to manage
without it, but I'll go get it just in case.
If we leave the city right now,
I don't think anyone will see us.
Go on ahead and
meet up with Torogai.
Listen, I think the water mill will
be fine without you going back...
it's just to be on the safe side.
Look after Chagum.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Commander.
The errand runner's
destination appears to be...
...the prince's and
spear-wielder's lair.
Are you certain?
No one was home, so we did not
see the prince with our own eyes...
...but judging from the neighbors'
description, it is almost certainly him.
What sort of place was it?
A water mill surrounded
on four sides by rice fields.
Zen is keeping watch, and
I've sent Taga and Sune on ahead.
What do you think, Commander?
Shall we launch a raid?
All right, let's join the others
and confirm that it's the prince.
Jin. You track down Master Shuga.
Sir?
Explain the situation to him
and have him wait here.
Surely it wouldn't be too late to
inform him after we have confirmation...
Jin...
You have a tendency to get overly
passionate where the prince is concerned.
Master Shuga is
a very prudent man.
Join the rest of us after
you've calmed down somewhat.
I've written down the location here.
Must dispatch pursuers...
Hiding here won't get me anywhere!
I've got to find a way to let
Balsa know what's going on!
There's just one of them.
If I run out the door and
break for the fields, maybe I can...
Son of a bitch!
I'm surrounded!
Jin...
What happened to you?
I found Prince Chagum...
You did?
Not long ago, I happened
upon him right over there...
Where is the prince now?
He was led away
by the bodyguard...
I don't believe this!
Damn, if only I had been
the one who met him...
I'm sorry. The fault is mine...
It happened so suddenly that
I found myself unable to do anything.
Where are the others?
Yun discovered a water mill that
appears to be the prince's hideout.
Everyone has left for it.
If the spear-wielder returns there with
the prince, everything will be resolved.
But if they remain at large, they...
Anyway, I will try to find them.
You wait at the inn.
I'm sorry. She was
headed eastwards.
I'm counting on you.
Now that it's come down to this...
I've got to make sure
Balsa and the others escape!
Commander!
She hasn't returned?
No.
I've stationed Rai and Hyok
on the farm roads just to be safe.
All we have to do is wait for the
spear-wielder to return with the prince.
Someone is inside!
That's not possible.
Knowing Balsa, she'll
figure out what this fire means.
It's on fire!
What happened?
Did embers in the hearth start a fire?
Hot! Ow! OW!
What's that?
That's the...
Were you the one
who set this fire?
The people who live here,
where did they go?
I don't know a thing! And even
if I did, I wouldn't tell you people!
You set it to warn off
the spear-wielder?
Damn.
Orders, sir?
The spear-wielder won't show
herself. Not with all this commotion...
She might be
somewhere nearby, though.
Should we bring him back
with us and make him talk?
No, the spear-wielder
is the cautious type.
I doubt that this boy
has been told anything.
Yes, maybe you're right.
Let's go.
I'm impressed that you thought
of setting the place on fire.
I respect your courage.
But you shouldn't risk your life like that.
I'm sorry, Toya. I'll never
forget this as long as I live.
Your Highness...
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you."
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
At the end of their path lies a Yakoo
village harkening back to bygone days.
Steam rises from earthenware pots.
The rice cakes are aromatic.
Next time,
"The Ancient Village."
Episode 18
The Ancient Village
But the storyteller
proclaims Chagum's death.