I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Is that you, Balsa?
You sure took your time.
We were worried that you'd been
captured by those people from the palace.
Where's Chagum?
Right here.
I've heard the particulars
of what happened.
We have no choice but to head
straight for Toumi village, then?
Yes.
Then let's hurry.
Balsa.
I want to go back to the palace and
find out what happened to my brother.
If it turns out that
he truly is dead, then I...
No. I can't allow you
to go back to the palace.
I'll explain why later.
Besides, the first thing we need
to do is to shake our pursuers!
Episode 18
The Ancient Village
How did the prince appear to you?
His appearance
had utterly changed.
To the extent that he would pass for
any child of the city at first glance...
He must have disguised
himself to prevent...
...residents of the
palace from finding him.
However...
One thing remained unchanged.
He seemed as lively and sound as ever.
I heard what happened
from Master Shuga.
Did you have any luck?
No, I searched all
over Ogi no Shimo.
I'm sorry. I have been
of no use whatsoever.
I am simply thankful that we have
confirmed that he is alive and well.
What is most important now is that
we do not fail in our next attempt.
Zen.
Sir.
What's this?
The goods that the errand runner
delivered to the spear-wielder.
She was preparing
to set out on a journey?
But from what I saw...
...the prince didn't seem to have
any clue until just a few hours before...
...that he was about
to go on the run again.
It appears that the spear-wielder
was planning to set out for somewhere...
...even before she
bumped into you, Master Shuga.
Fortunately, the contents of this pack
will allow us to deduce her destination.
I see.
Judging from these quantities, she was
planning a three-day trip with the prince.
This is not enough to cross
the Misty Blue Mountains.
From this, we can deduce
that they will either go south...
...on the Tonan highway or they'll enter
the mountainous region to the east.
There is no chance that they
will go to Rota or Sangal?
It's hard to believe that they would
make for the border carrying provisions.
There are any number
of inns along the way.
I see.
In that case, I shall start by dispatching
runners to the Tonan highway barrier.
That will make it a simple
matter to find the prince...
...on the single road
leading to the coast.
Which leaves the
mountains to the east.
Yes.
Now why would the
bodyguard travel east?
They aren't as high
as the Misty Blues...
...but the area is largely unexplored
and covered with primeval forests.
I can't think of anything there besides
a handful of Yakoo settlements.
That's it! The Yakoo!
When I met the bodyguard, I was
perplexed by her words and actions.
She seemed to know
even more about...
...the spirit within
Prince Chagum than I do.
I wondered how someone
from Kanbal could know so much.
She must have gained this
knowledge from the Yakoo.
I see.
That would also explain the
mud dolls we found on the valley floor...
...instead of the prince and her
up in the Misty Blue Mountains.
There is a Yakoo settlement called
Yashiro village beyond the terrace fields...
...where we first
crossed swords with her.
So she had a Yakoo accomplice
in addition to the errand runner...
Perhaps, but a trip to Yashiro
wouldn't call for such preparations.
And even if they intended to travel to
a settlement farther off in that direction...
...I doubt they would travel to their initial
destination now that we've located them.
I will keep that possibility
in mind, of course.
I will have them step up surveillance
on the Sangal and Rota barriers.
Master Shuga, perhaps it would be
wise to summon troops right away...
...to check every highway, as well as
search Kosenkyo from top to bottom.
That would take far too long.
And one other thing, Mon.
I cannot help but think that the bodyguard
is thinking the same thing I am.
I believe that she needs to find a fresh
source of information, just as I do.
Are you all right?
Let me carry you on my back.
Go on, don't be shy.
Walk on your own
two feet, Chagum.
It's all right, Balsa. I'm fine.
If he carries you, who's
going to carry his pack?
Torogai?
Me?
Or is Tanda going to carry
both you and his own pack?
Come on, you don't
have to be like that.
Fine, I'll walk on my own.
And while we're walking, tell me
about the egg that's inside me.
Tell me what's more important
than my brother dying!
There's no time for that now.
What's the matter?
We're lost.
I see. So Toya...
That's right. If he hadn't
risked his life like that...
...I probably wouldn't be
standing here right now.
Torogai is taking forever.
Well, it's been quite a while
since she last went to Toumi.
No, that's not it. This is just her way
of showing concern for Chagum.
I see. Actually, I've been
to Toumi once myself.
But I don't remember anything
about how to get there.
I was brought there by my uncle when
I was even younger than Chagum.
That's a shame.
My grandmother on my mother's
side came from Toumi village.
Initially, she left Toumi
to marry my grandfather...
...but once my mother married into
the family, they both retired to Toumi.
Did I ever tell you about that?
No. Are they still alive?
I'm not sure. Probably not.
How are you planning to tell Chagum?
You know, about the egg-eater...
I don't know. It's a touchy subject.
Plus, his brother died recently.
Maybe you should wait until he's had
a chance to come to terms with that.
No, we'll have to talk to
him about it eventually.
This isn't something that
we can keep from him forever.
He'll have to learn the truth
and gain strength from it.
So once we reach Toumi and find
some way to fight it, I'll tell him.
Rejoice. I found the way through.
Also, I found us some food.
The vagrants who use this as a
shelter appear to have seen them.
It's almost certain
that it was the prince.
Yes. Both that old woman and the
Yakoo man are likely her accomplices.
We just spotted a smoke
signal from Zen and Yun.
There doesn't appear to be any sign of
the spear-wielder stopping at Tokal village.
Taga and Sune were
investigating other settlements...
...and they sent the same signal.
In which case,
all that's left is Toumi.
I've heard that Toumi
is one of the few villages...
...where the ancient Yakoo
ways have been preserved.
All right, we will go on ahead.
Wait a moment, sir.
The terrain between here and Toumi
is difficult by horse, much less on foot.
Jin and I will go on ahead first.
I believe the safest
course of action...
...is for you to rendezvous with
the others and follow our lead.
So we can't go by horse?
Very well. I will join you later.
However, even if you
catch sight of the prince...
...please do not take
any action until I arrive.
There is something that
I want to ask them in person.
Understood.
We shall do as you wish.
Teacher, are you sure
this is a shortcut?
This should save us half a day.
Still not ripe, huh...
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Weather in the mountains
sure changes quickly.
Which means this will
let up soon enough.
There are no traces of them,
but I find that all the more suspicious.
I concur.
But there are no
clues to follow, either.
Looks like we'll soon have our
first proper meal in two days.
You're hungry too,
aren't you, Chagum?
A monkey?
No, a person.
Are you from around here?
Um...
Are you related to Kunda?
I see now. You must
know my grandfather.
Yes. Kunda was always
very good to my family...
...so I could tell right away that
you were related to him, Tanda.
I see. You must look
like your grandfather.
By the way,
would that happen to be...
Oh, this? This is mashira liquor
that I gathered in the mountains.
I knew it!
Teacher.
This is called a "road's end rope."
it's a charm where you rattle
the nahji bird bones strung on it...
...to prevent evil
spirits from entering.
I've seen these in
Yogo villages from time to time.
That's just the Yogo people
imitating Yakoo traditions.
The proper way to do it is to string it
up across the entrance to a village.
Let's go. It looks like Toumi
village is just across that hill.
It's as if the Yakoo way of life before
the Yogoans arrived is preserved here.
I suppose they don't often
see people like Chagum and me.
I suppose not.
So good of you to come!
I'm Soya, the village headman.
It's been many a year since we
last had outsiders visit our village.
Are you him? The one they
say is Kunda's grandson?
You're his spitting image, all right!
I regret to tell you that Kunda
passed away two years ago.
Actually, we didn't come
here to visit my grandfather.
We hope to gain insight from
your knowledge of the old ways.
We have a lot of questions for
you about the Nyunga Ro Chaga.
Standing out here talking
won't do any good.
First, please come to my home.
We'll talk afterwards.
Why in the world did you come all this
way to ask about some old legend?
Well, we're in a bit of
a complicated situation.
If possible, we'd like to ask your
storyteller detailed questions about...
...the changing of the Nyunga Ro Im
that happened a hundred years ago.
Oh, is it almost time again for the
changing of the protector of the waters?
Yes, just about.
Then, in a sense, you're in luck.
I've heard that my father's
older brother, who died young...
...was a Nyunga Ro Chaga.
Is that true?
Yes, but my grandmother was so full
of grief whenever she spoke of him...
...that I don't remember
much in the way of details.
What's more, my mother was
the village's last storyteller.
She died last year, so there
is hardly anyone left in the village...
...who can tell you much about
the Nyunga Ro Chaga now.
Why did you abandon
your storyteller traditions?
As I'm sure you're aware, the training
to become a storyteller is most harsh.
From an early age,
you are forced to learn...
...thousands of oral traditions
from sunup to sundown.
It is cruel to force all
that on any one person.
I didn't care much for such practices,
so I decided not to appoint a successor.
And besides, we now have the
official history of Shin Yogo to consult.
Shameful! So this place is no
different from the palace after all.
Excuse me...
I heard stories about the Nyunga
Ro Chaga from my grandmother...
...so I think I can tell
you a few of them.
Come to think of it, you used to visit my
mother carrying yamabime, didn't you?
Anything you can tell us
would be appreciated.
Can you tell us what you
heard from your grandmother?
Yes.
According to my grandmother...
...in the body of my great-grandfather's
older brother, the one who died young...
...the egg of Nyunga Ro Im
suddenly appeared.
Nyunga Ro Im is a spirit who lives
deep underwater in Nayug's seas...
...and is shaped
like a giant shellfish.
The life force from its mouth becomes
clouds in Sagu and creates rain.
But once every hundred years,
Nyunga Ro Im lays an egg and dies.
When that happens,
the clouds vanish from the skies...
...and we experience
a period of dry weather.
She said we have cared for the
guardian of the spirit since ancient times...
...so that the egg of the
next spirit would hatch safely.
But that is usually only
until the egg matures.
When the time comes for
Nyunga Ro Im's egg to hatch...
...the guardian travels alone to the
land of feasting, never to be seen again.
Overcome with grief,
my great-grandmother's mother...
...begged the people of the village
to help protect her son as well...
...as he had become
a guardian of the spirit.
You know, I remember
hearing about that myself.
Master Shuga, it's a
signal from the commander.
It looks like there is
a shortcut in that direction.
I see.
And beyond it lies Toumi.
So, what did the villagers do
with the Nyunga Ro Chaga?
When the spring day
of equality drew near...
...the Nyunga Ro Chaga left the village
like a bird beginning its migration.
The adult villagers
followed him on his long journey.
At long last, they reached a large spring
at the headwaters of the Aoyumi River...
...where the shigu salua
bloomed everywhere.
There, the guardian of the spirit
prepared to return the egg to Nayug.
But Rarunga had also come
to this spring from Nayug.
Like an egg-eating snake striking its prey,
Rarunga attacked the Nyunga Ro Chaga.
And before the eyes
of the watching adults...
...using enormous claws that could
be neither seen nor felt by humans...
...it ripped the
Nyunga Ro Chaga in two.
Am I... Am I going to die
like that too, Balsa?
Die like what?
Who in the world is this child?
The fact is, this boy is
the current Nyunga Ro Chaga.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
It is when they are beaten down by
fate that people reveal their true selves.
They become distressed, angry,
and then they cross paths.
Next time, "Escape."
Episode 19
Escape
Balsa wields her weapon
filled with determination.