I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Looks like he's settled down.
So...what are we
going to do about this?
Episode 19
Escape
I can hardly believe that
Shin-Yogo's second prince...
...would end up being
the Nyunga Ro Chaga.
If you like, we can protect him
here in the village until spring.
Certain circumstances won't
allow us to accept your offer.
What should I do?
Look at what I did to the prince.
It's all right. It's not your fault.
It happened because
we were careless, not you.
He's asleep. It looks like the
shock has started to wear off.
I see.
Nimka, please tell us
the rest of that story.
We already knew that the
egg-eater would be coming.
The reason we
hadn't told him anything...
...was that we'd intended to do it after
we'd found a way to drive it off.
Please.
You said that the egg-eater
couldn't be seen or touched.
What did you mean by that?
I don't know.
That's just what I was taught.
But she said that it
was clearly visible when...
...it was tearing the
Nyunga Ro Chaga apart.
They said they saw many claws
coming out of the ground.
Many claws?
It sounds like trouble,
whatever it is.
Nimka, did your great-grandmother
tell you anything else?
What the egg-eater
didn't like, for instance?
Not surprising...
If they knew anything, they would
have tried it a hundred years ago.
I'm sorry. I wish I had something
encouraging to tell you...
...but she said that the Nyunga Ro
Chaga is destined to be devoured by it.
So it seems that the
Yona Ro Gai spoke the truth...
But if it ate him, egg and all...
...we wouldn't have been blessed
with water like we have been.
That means that the egg
hatched safely a century ago.
So why not the
Nyunga Ro Chaga also?
I think... the Nyunga Ro Chaga can
only deposit the egg here in Sagu...
...by being ripped open by Rarunga.
The say that Nyunga Ro Im
is a spirit born in Sagu's oceans...
...that makes its way upriver, and lives
at the bottom of Nayug's deep waters.
That's why it's necessary for
the egg to be deposited here first.
Maybe this egg-eater Rarunga...
...is one of the forces of nature that
allows Sagu and Nayug to interact.
If that's true, how does the egg travel
from the headwaters of the Aoyumi...
...all the way to the sea
once it's deposited here?
Does it travel down
the river on its own?
It's like it says in
the rice-planting song.
A nahji bird picks up the egg
in its beak and carries it to sea.
Rice-planting song?
The one that goes "Nahji, fly, fly"?
The third verse of the song goes...
..."Go, nahji, go, take the ball in your
beak and fly up above the claws," right?
Did the lyrics really say that?
That verse isn't sung much
around Yogo farm villages any more.
People thought it was a bit vulgar.
But that is certainly how we
used to sing it back in the old days.
So the line "If you fly to the sea, the
rains will fall and the seedlings will grow"...
...was actually the
fourth verse, then?
Taken as a whole, it could mean that
a nahji will rescue Nyunga Ro lm's egg...
...from the egg-eater's claws
and carry it to the sea...
...where it will grow into
a spirit and cause rain to fall.
Of all the luck... That just leaves us
with an even bigger problem.
The nahji!
You people are
so slow to catch on...
When was the last time
any of you saw a nahji?
Now that you mention it...
...I used to see the sky filled
with nahji as they flew south.
Lately, though...
They've become even rarer
since Yogo started working steel.
Even bones for charms against evil
spirits are hard to come by these days.
At this rate,
we might not be able to...
...carry the water spirit safely to
the sea, let alone protect the boy.
It looks like we lost more
in the past hundred years...
...than just our customs
and oral traditions.
Commander!
Taga? Where is Master Shuga?
He is about six nan
away from here.
In that case, we should reach
Toumi sometime before noon.
Yes. Master Shuga appears tired,
but he should make it.
Jin, travel on ahead to Toumi
and scout the area.
Understood.
Taga, Sune. Go with him.
Yes, sir!
Well, then, we'll be in the
main house across the way.
Look, Balsa...
Not even you can fight
something that you can't see.
Plus, if Chagum has to be killed for
the egg to be deposited here in Sagu...
...we should just run
someplace far away.
We can't. Even if
we run from here...
...there's no escaping the destiny
he's been burdened with.
Not unless we fight
to find another way.
Also, I gave my word
that I wouldn't let him die.
I'll do whatever it takes to save him.
Torogai, can you think of anything?
Some way to both save Chagum and
allow the water spirit's egg to hatch?
I don't know.
At any rate, we still have
some time before spring comes...
...so let's come up
with something else.
Besides, if the palace
has sent out pursuers...
...we can't assume
that we'll be safe here.
We should move somewhere
else as soon as possible.
How about Hunter's Hole, then?
Good idea. We might be able to
prepare for things if we go there too.
Um, I'm sorry about earlier.
I didn't mean to tell you
such a terrible story.
That's all right.
If you hadn't told us the story then...
...I'd still be completely in the dark.
It's allowed me to
make up my mind.
I'm going back to the palace
by myself. Back to my mother.
The spirit's egg has made me suffer
one terrible ordeal after another.
I can't take it any more.
Wait!
I'll take you there.
It's no wonder that you're scared.
Even if you are the guardian of the spirit,
I'm sure you don't want to be eaten.
So I'll take you there.
What do we do? Infiltrate the
village and get confirmation?
No, people will come out to
the fields once the sun comes up.
When they do, we'll ask them
about the goings-on in the village.
We don't want to alert the
spear-wielder to our presence.
Master Shuga, we've
been awaiting your arrival.
I've sent Jin and others on ahead.
Please get some rest now,
and we'll set out at dawn.
Very well.
But I doubt there'll be
much time for rest...
Excuse me.
Is Nimka still with
you in your quarters?
Nimka? I think she and the headman
went back to the main house last night.
When I checked on her earlier, it
looked like her bed hadn't been slept in.
I thought that perhaps she was telling
you more of the stories that she knows.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Only the people of Toumi
know about this path.
If we follow this, we can reach
the Yashiro village area in two days.
I'm sorry. Those two left the
village, and we had no idea.
Well, the area is like Nimka's backyard,
so I'm not worried about her.
But if anything happens
to the Nyunga Ro Chaga...
So, did you figure out
when they left?
Yes, a man said that he noticed
the dogs barking at daybreak.
It must have been
sometime around then.
Balsa is out looking for them...
...so I expect she'll bring
them back soon enough.
As for us, we need to
get ready to leave.
Nice day, isn't it?
I'm sorry if I startled you,
but I'd like to ask you some questions.
I believe that an outlander woman
and a Yogo boy are visiting the village.
Do you know where
I might find them?
Yes, they're staying at
the village headman's place.
It's the furthest building
from the village entrance.
You'll be able to tell
which one it is right away.
Ah, I see. There wasn't anyone else
travelling with them, was there?
There was a Yakoo man and a magic
weaver who looked like his grandmother.
But they were talking about possibly
leaving the village this morning...
...so they might have left for
wherever they were headed already.
This grandmother you mentioned...
...was she an old woman about
this tall carrying a strange staff?
Yes, that's right...
Commander, we should hurry.
What's the matter?
For a moment, it was like I was
somehow looking on a different landscape...
Are you all right?
Balsa?
Chagum, we're going
back to the village.
I won't go.
Why did you keep
everything from me?
About the egg-eater...
About me dying...
You knew all along, didn't you?
Yes.
The reason I kept it
from you until now...
...is because we didn't
know anything for sure.
I didn't want to
worry you needlessly.
Liar!
The egg is more important
to you than I am, Balsa.
That's not true.
You and the egg are both precious
things that deserve to be protected.
Deserve to be protected?
Balsa, you don't need to
worry about me any more.
I'm returning to the palace.
You aren't my mother,
so you can't...
You have no idea how
I'm suffering, so you don't...
I see. If you want to
go back that badly...
Use that to kill me first.
Once I've set my mind to do something,
nothing can make me budge.
I won't let you go
back to the palace.
If you insist on going
anyway, pick that up!
All right...
Now then, run me through with it!
Balsa, no matter
how tough you are...
...you're no match for some
monster with gigantic claws!
I'm going back to the palace to have
Shuga and my mother protect me!
How dare you raise a weapon
against your parent!
We're all trying our hardest
to protect you, Chagum!
What were you thinking,
running off on your own?
I'll protect you no matter what.
Plus, you're the
guardian of the spirit.
So even if you're scared...
...you have to keep fighting to
the bitter end to protect the egg!
Even if it costs me my life,
I won't let you die!
So please, I'm asking
you to have faith in me!
Why me?
Why does it have to be me?
Is the village headman here?
We believe the second prince of the
Shin-Yogo empire is in this village!
We are envoys of the mikado sent
here from Kosenkyo to retrieve him!
We request an immediate audience!
Wouldn't it be faster
to follow this river?
Yes, but if we take the
prince into consideration...
...a slightly more level route
would probably be better.
You have a point.
Soya!
A man with warriors in the square
says they've been sent by the palace...
He says they've
come for the prince!
Torogai?
We slipped up...
They're here already?
I'll go and hear what
they have to say.
You hide yourselves and wait here.
Goodness gracious, what a treat
to have visitors from so far away!
Are you the village headman?
Yes, I have that honor.
Good, that simplifies matters.
Bring out the prince at once.
I'm sorry. I'm afraid I can't do that.
What's the meaning of this?
You see, just as he is
precious to you as your prince...
...to us Yakoo, he is also
the guardian of the spirit...
...he who nurtures the
protector of the water within him.
If the egg he bears
within him fails to hatch...
...these lands will never again
be blessed with water.
So you see, this is why
we can't bring him to you.
We are also aware of these facts.
As such, none of us
wishes him any harm.
On the contrary, we are here so that
we may keep him safe and sound.
My people cannot live without
the blessings of water, either.
If your people care at all for
this land, or for Shin-Yogo...
...will you entrust both him
and the spirit's egg to our care?
You speak of country, but that has little
bearing on the lives of the people here.
Besides, we Yakoo
have protected...
...the Nyunga Ro Chaga ourselves
for generation after generation.
Just as we did when one of our own
was the Nyunga Ro Chaga a century ago.
So I ask that you allow
us Yakoo to see to this...
Bring out the prince while
we're still asking politely.
Otherwise, this village
will be wiped off the map.
That's not a very civil
tone to take, is it?
Spear-wielder! Are you listening?
You won't get away
like you did before!
We'll do everything in our
power to bring you down!
I don't know what your motive is,
dragging the prince around with you...
...but your work is done!
Come out peacefully!
Quiet, you noisy brats!
What's all this shouting about?
Wait a minute, isn't he...
I am Torogai the magic weaver!
The prince and the spear-wielder
are no longer here!
If you have something
to say, say it to me!
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
His heart filled with unavoidable
emotions, Chagum walks on.
And on... And on...
Next time, "To Hunter's Hole."
Episode 20
To Hunter's Hole
One man's fate can't be
shouldered by another.
What would you do in his place?