I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Spear-wielder! Are you listening?
You won't get away
like you did before!
We'll do everything in our
power to bring you down!
I don't know what your motive is,
dragging the prince around with you...
...but your work is done!
Come out peacefully!
Quiet, you noisy brats!
What's all this shouting about?
Wait a minute, isn't he...
Episode 20
To Hunter's Hole
You there. Are you a star reader?
I am. Torogai, I wish that we had
had the chance to meet sooner.
That's the last thing I expected
to hear from a star reader.
Ah, now I see.
It was you who had the second
queen write a letter to me, wasn't it?
Indeed it was.
In that case, we might be able
to have a proper discussion.
Young star reader, I want to hear
your thoughts on this matter.
Torogai?
Your prince has been made
the Nyunga Ro Chaga.
Apparently, when next year's
spring day of equality arrives...
...he will set out for a place
called the land of feasting...
...just like a migratory bird
taking flight on its journey.
Also, I have learned that an egg-eater
will also come here from Nayug.
Egg-eater?
Just like a brown bear coming
to feast on toburya...
...that are swimming
upstream to spawn.
And according to Yakoo legends,
the guardian of the spirit...
...is destined to be killed
by the egg-eater at this time.
You're saying that
the prince will die?
Yes, that's what I'm saying!
Don't make me repeat myself!
What is the extent of your knowledge
regarding the Nyunga Ro Chaga?
Are there no stories about
the guardian of the spirit...
...escaping this fate in the past?
No, at least not in
Yakoo oral traditions.
Magic weaver of Yakoo...
If what you say is true...
...is it not all the more reason
to turn the prince over to us?
I don't know what sort of
creature this "egg-eater" is...
...but the army of Yogo is
in excess of 10,000 men.
Even if a demon like the one described
in the official history should appear...
...it will be a simple matter
for us to defend the prince.
Will it still be a simple matter
if it's a monster from Nayug...
...that can be neither seen
or touched by human beings?
To something from Nayug...
...the walls and spearmen surrounding
your palace won't mean a thing.
No matter how hard you try
to hide the prince, in the end...
...it will reach out from Nayug with
its invisible claws and tear him apart.
Knowing this, are you still telling me
that you'll be able to do anything...
...to stop the egg-eater
if we give him to you?
I have access to the epitaphs left
by the original master star reader.
If we can read and
decipher them, perhaps we...
What the... You've had something
that important all this time...
...and you haven't
even read it all yet?
That insolent whelp Hibi Tonan
must have gone senile.
This proves we can't hand over the
precious Nyunga Ro Chaga to that nitwit!
You're saying that the Yakoo
can protect him, then?
Of course!
That's why the spear-wielder...
...has already taken the
prince to a secret location.
If you think I'm lying, feel free to
search the village from top to bottom.
But you must understand that she isn't
simply refusing to hand over the prince.
It just means that she wants to
protect both the prince and the egg.
If you people want
to save the prince...
...go back and read
those epitaphs or whatever...
...and come meet us at the land of
feasting on the spring day of equality!
We will be waiting for you there.
Enough of this! Prince Chagum
is our prince of Yogo.
We'll protect him ourselves!
We don't need help from you Yakoo!
Will you cut down
everyone in this village?
If you think that will save your
prince and this land, then do it!
But if you blindly
return with the prince...
...the Nayug creature will
follow you to the palace.
Wait! Pointless slaughter
will accomplish nothing here.
Put away your swords!
Torogai, it would appear
that we star readers...
...have become quite
arrogant over the years.
Compared to your people,
our knowledge is sorely lacking.
Your men don't seem to
be of the same opinion.
For now, I will leave
this place with my men.
But by the time of the
spring day of equality...
...I will find a way to save Prince
Chagum, and we will surely return here.
When we do, I expect that you
will return Prince Chagum to us!
Master Shuga!
Silence!
You tried with all your might, and
still you couldn't kill this bodyguard.
Entrusting the prince to her until
spring is the safest course of action.
Jin, perhaps what
Master Shuga says is right.
For now, put away your sword.
Magic weaver,
is His Highness in good health?
In that case, Torogai, let us meet
again in the land of feasting next spring.
Are you Torogai's apprentice?
That's right...
Thank you for your
assistance that day.
Your information regarding mantis
eggs was the key that led me here.
I am grateful.
We haven't a moment to lose.
As soon as we
return to the palace...
...I must organize a team
to read through the epitaphs.
He remembered me. I'm surprised.
You've met that star reader before?
Yes, once. On the outskirts
of Ogi no Shimo.
I have to admit, Torogai...
...I'm amazed you managed to
come up with a lie like that on the spot.
Once Balsa gets back,
we'll set out for Hunter's Hole.
Are you sure that
you can't stay here?
Thank you, but no.
There are certain preparations
that I want the boy to make.
I see.
Thank you for helping us.
We have no intention of
spending the winter idly.
Leave the Nyunga Ro Chaga to us.
We are all counting on you.
This is shikul honey
that Nimka collected.
Please enjoy it while you
are holed up in the cave.
Thank you.
Please take care.
All right, we should get going.
Be careful.
What's this? They're seeing us off?
What are they bowing for?
They do it to show their
respect toward the one...
...who shoulders the destiny
that someone had to bear.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Whoa!
It is Shuga.
Master Gakai, are you there?
Master Shuga?
Master Gakai is currently...
it's all right. Come in.
Pardon the interruption.
What do you want?
I have come because
I wish to ask for your help.
With Crown Prince Sagum dead...
...I have been removed from
my post of tutor-governor.
While you, on the other hand...
...now hold authority on par with
the master star reader himself.
That being the case,
why not simply give me an order?
After all, I have no right to refuse.
Master Gakai,
I travelled to Toumi village.
There, I learned to my chagrin...
...that star readers' knowledge pales
in comparison to that of the Yakoo.
Nevertheless, we must now
surpass even their knowledge.
That doesn't concern me.
I beg to differ.
This concerns not only Shin-Yogo...
...but everyone who lives
on the Nayoro peninsula!
Master Gakai, do me
the honor of assisting me...
...by taking charge of our
epitaph-deciphering efforts!
You are conversant in
every field of knowledge...
...and you possess a
deeply inquisitive mind.
Only one man is capable of keeping
this project running smoothly!
Master Gakai, that man is you!
This area is colder
than it is in Kosenkyo...
...so the leaves
change color much earlier.
He's been like that
ever since we left Toumi.
Yes, but at least we're
almost at Hunter's Hole.
We'll worry about Chagum
after we get there.
True.
I swear, you leave this place vacant
for a while and look what happens.
Torogai and I made
a few improvements...
...in the cavern here
beneath the rock.
Wait here. We'll go light some fires.
Jiguro...
I'm back.
Okay, we've got some lights going!
Try making your way down.
I have to get him to hold
his head high like he used to.
Surprised? We call this part
of the cave the entry hall.
But it's too open and cold out here,
so we set up the rooms further in.
Follow me.
The hole on the right extends so far that
it's like a maze, so don't go in there.
There's a spring in the middle one.
The one on the left is our home.
This is the living room.
Over there is a room where
we smoke meats or whatever.
Over there is the storehouse
for supplies and water.
There doesn't seem to be
any obvious damage.
This place never changes, does it?
Every last detail is
exactly like it was.
This is the first time I've been
back here since Jiguro died.
We'll be penned in here
once it starts snowing.
There's a lot that we
need to see to before then.
We need to get ready to
hole up for the winter right away.
You give it a try too.
If we don't prepare them like this,
they won't smoke properly.
Okay, I think I'll go
make us some tea.
Once we're done with these,
we'll turn in early.
We're going out first thing
in the morning to set traps.
All right.
You clean it just like
you would a hare.
Give it a try on your own.
This place is pretty much full.
This should be more than enough
to keep us fed through winter.
Tanda, do you have
any insect galls?
I want to tan some hides.
Sure.
I'm going to borrow this
mortar and pestle too.
Go ahead.
Balsa, is this enough?
That'll be plenty. Thank you.
It looks to me like that boy
has toughened up quite a bit.
He's enduring
Balsa's tough training too.
True, but I'm worried that
he hardly ever says anything.
He has to work that
through on his own.
We can try to talk to him as
much as we want, but in the end...
...it's the boy who has to accept
the fate of the Nyunga Ro Chaga.
What's the matter?
Let me see.
Your hand is chapped.
Wait, I'll put some salve on it.
Hang in there. This medicine
might sting, but it works wonders.
Back when I was your age,
my hands were rubbed raw a lot too.
And every time, Jiguro rubbed
this salve on them for me.
He was usually very strict...
...but whenever my hands were chapped,
he became gentle for some reason.
This Jiguro person...
Was he the man who raised you?
Yes, he was my foster father,
and the man I owe my life to.
The man you owe your life to?
Right.
Come to think of it, I never
did tell you about him, did I?
If it weren't for Jiguro,
I probably wouldn't be here today.
I would have been killed
when I was six, no question.
Will you tell me about him?
You know, maybe this is
the right time to tell you.
As you know,
my homeland of Kanbal...
...is a small country that lies
beyond the Misty Blue Mountains.
Even in a place like that, people
constantly want to start conflicts.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
With pleading eyes,
he begged his friend.
"Look after my daughter," he said.
Next time, "Jiguro Musa."
Episode 21
Jiguro Musa
Why did I quit the King's Spears?