I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
To tell you about Jiguro, I should start
by telling you about my childhood.
Unlike Yogo, Kanbal has no fields
that produce bountiful harvests.
All it has are steep mountains
and rocky grasslands.
The people make a living
by tilling the poor soil...
...eking out what little grain
and potatoes they can from it...
...and by grazing Kanbal goats.
That's the kind of place
I was born and raised in.
Episode 21
Jiguro Musa
My father, Karna Yonsa, was the
royal family's personal physician.
My mother died when I was five,
but thanks to my father...
...I led a happy life,
never wanting for anything.
I was too young to realize it,
but by that point...
...my father was already caught up
in a situation he couldn't get out of.
My father, chief physician
to the king of Kanbal...
...had been ordered to
poison the king by Logsam...
...the king's younger brother,
who had his eyes on the throne.
Logsam had threatened to
kill his daughter if he refused.
And so my father had
no choice but to agree.
However, he knew that as soon as
he'd succeeded in poisoning the king...
...his and his daughter's lives would
be forfeit because of what he knew.
Caught up in Logsam's machinations,
my father found himself isolated.
But he had one friend in the palace
that he trusted implicitly.
That man was Jiguro.
Jiguro was a member
of the King's Spears...
...a group of nine men
who served the king.
The King's Spears was
comprised of elite spear-wielders...
...the leaders of Kanbal's
nine ethnic tribes.
Jiguro was the youngest man ever
to be elected to the King's Spears...
...and was lauded as
Kanbal's most powerful hero.
Although my father regretted
involving his friend in this terrible plot...
...he resolved to reveal
Logsam's plot to Jiguro.
In a matter of days, I will administer
the final dose of poison to the king.
Once the king is dead,
I will inevitably be punished.
But my daughter is
completely innocent.
You are the only one I can turn to.
I realize that I'm asking you
to do the impossible.
Ever since my wife passed away, though,
Balsa has been my entire world.
I beg you, take my daughter
and flee the country.
Apparently, Jiguro refused
my father's request.
It's no wonder.
Even though the request came
from Jiguro's close friend...
...to accept would mean forfeiting
not only his status and honor...
...but it would also
spell his own doom.
In the evening of that same day,
palace soldiers came to our home.
Logsam must have already figured
out what my father was planning.
I'm here at the request of your father.
Come with me right now.
Although he had initially
refused my father...
...for some reason, he said these words,
took my hesitant hand in his...
...and we left our
homeland of Kanbal.
Jiguro...forgive me...
If Jiguro hadn't come
for me when he did...
...I'm certain that I would
have been killed that day.
We then spent an entire day traversing
the long caves along the Kanbal border...
...eventually crossing into the
territory of the Shin-Yogo empire.
I was completely exhausted,
but I couldn't sleep at all that night.
For one thing, Jiguro hadn't
explained anything to me...
...and his tension was contagious.
Jiguro was on his guard,
alert for approaching pursuers.
Five days after we began our flight,
our first pursuer found us.
The man who appeared
was one of the King's Spears.
At first, I had no idea that the
man was there to hunt us down.
After all, the two of them
were speaking so calmly.
Was it Logsam who
sent you after us?
Logsam is an even worse
tyrant than I imagined.
That's true.
But this has given me the chance to
fulfil a dream that I've had for years.
I've always felt a
sense of dissatisfaction...
...over the fact that I haven't
had a chance to challenge you...
...ever since you achieved the
top rank in the King's Spears.
I also have to question
if it's truly necessary...
...for a spear dance to be
part of a life-or-death struggle.
You do, do you?
Perhaps it's because I had
those very same feelings...
...that I find myself
standing here right now.
What are you doing?
Are you mocking me?
No. This is a genuine
fight to the death.
I'm sorry.
I can never return to Kanbal.
And so I can't bring you
back to our homeland.
Let's go.
It was obvious that Jiguro had
not tried to avoid fighting that man.
To this day,
I still don't understand why.
But since he had reached
the top at such a young age...
...maybe he wanted, just once,
to see what he was really capable of.
That might have just been
wishful thinking on my part...
...wanting to believe that the
brief fight had nothing to do with me.
At the same time,
though, it struck me...
...that my situation was even
more dire than I ever imagined.
I realized that my only hope of
survival was to go with this man.
After that encounter,
we entered a city in Yogo...
...to get a replacement spearhead
for Jiguro's broken spear.
That swordsmith was
stubborn even back then.
At first, he refused to take the job.
If at all possible, I'd like
to avoid killing anyone else...
...but I have no idea what
that number may even be.
As I know you have the skills to do so,
I would like you to forge me a spear...
...that is equal to any Yogo sword.
The implications of what
Jiguro was saying terrified me...
...so I avoided listening to
the rest of their conversation.
After thinking a while, the swordsmith
said the following to Jiguro.
"In seven days,
pay me another visit."
The next seven days
seemed like an eternity.
For one thing, Jiguro didn't
even try to speak to me.
It's finally started
to snow out there.
Has it, now?
I thought it felt colder.
I'll go make some tea.
Are those two upstairs?
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Jiguro, we're already soaked to
the bone. Let's rest here a while!
Don't stop! What will
we do if we catch cold?
Just keep running until
we reach the city.
What's wrong?
Stay here.
Well, well.
I knew you would
be the second...
Tagul!
I knew that you would come here.
So, what did Logsam tell you?
Did he order you to kill the
co-conspirators of the physician...
...who poisoned the king?
So, you've taken the
oath not to hear or speak?
I know better than anyone that
you're a man who dislikes combat.
Your wife and children are being
held hostage, aren't they?
Tagul!
So you too...have found
something to protect...at last?
Tagul...
When I saw Jiguro
break down into sobs...
...I didn't know what I should do.
I thought, "This is the only man
I can turn to. What can I do for him?"
And later on, I learned the
real reason for Jiguro's tears.
The second assassin that
Logsam had sent after us...
...was Jiguro's closest friend
among all the King's Spears.
But, no...
Logsam was an
utterly fearsome man...
...and he was utterly
without scruples.
We returned to the Yogo city,
and from a Kanbal migrant worker...
...we learned that my
father had been killed.
I had always thought that I would
see my father again someday.
For the first time since
we left Kanbal, I cried.
For someone at my age, that was
the worst possible news I could hear.
Jiguro then told me
everything that was going on...
...almost as if he were
speaking to an adult.
He explained why my father
had been killed...
...and why I had had to
flee the country with him.
The hatred that blossomed
inside my heart that day...
...still sits like a lump
deep inside me.
That wish to get my revenge
against Logsam one day.
Sol asked Jiguro to
teach me martial arts.
Jiguro! Teach me how to fight!
But Jiguro wouldn't
agree to my request.
No.
The martial arts
are a man's domain.
Women's muscles prevent them...
...from making any real headway
no matter how hard they try.
And most of all, you're just a child.
Even though he'd turned me down
so bluntly, I couldn't give up.
From then on, I secretly watched
Jiguro train whenever I got the chance...
...to try to pick up how
to use a short spear.
Some time after that...
...Jiguro was working as an
escort for a merchant caravan.
For us, this killed three
birds with one stone.
The first was that it allowed Jiguro
to make a living using his martial arts.
The second was that
I was continuously...
...able to witness
Jiguro in combat firsthand.
This gave me invaluable
insight into the martial arts.
And the third was that this allowed us
to quickly gather information...
...on the people
who were pursuing us.
Six people apparently
searching for us?
Jiguro, look!
These are your moves, Jiguro!
Seeing the amused looks on the
faces of the adults around me...
...caused me to get carried away.
That man went for your
spear hand, remember?
And you let go of your spear for a
second, dodged his strike, and then...
Don't ever do that again!
Is that clear?
Why did you do that?
Who can say? I'm not really sure.
Maybe after seeing the worried
look on his face, I wanted to help.
Or maybe I just wanted
to get a rise out of him.
After all, that man never
talked to me about anything.
But not long after that, Jiguro
began to train me in the martial arts.
Why?
I think that one reason is that he was
impressed by my little performance.
At the time, I had no idea that
what I did was extraordinary...
...but apparently, I had
a gift for the martial arts.
At any rate, I had
pretty much memorized...
...all of Jiguro's fighting
moves just by watching.
But there was something else.
One other reason.
Another reason?
Starting today, practice with this.
A short spear isn't
created to fit a body.
You must make
your body fit the spear.
Why the change of heart?
I thought you didn't want to force
the girl to live a life of bloodshed.
It's true that for any
student of the martial arts...
...the more proficient you become...
...the more opponents
you draw to yourself.
As much as I hate to say it,
this path is her only hope of survival.
You've figured that out, have you?
Jiguro must have already
caught wind of the rumors...
...that the remaining King's Spears
had joined forces to hunt us down.
And so, he began
training me in the martial arts...
...so that I would be able to
survive in the event of his death.
Even so, Jiguro
was a cautious man.
He hoped to avoid having to kill
any more of his friends if he could...
...so we lived up in Yogo's
mountains until our money ran out...
...and didn't take on any
high-profile bodyguard jobs.
Ah, and that's when you met
Tanda and Mistress Torogai.
Right.
Living that way allowed us
to evade the pursuit...
...of the King's Spears
for nearly ten years.
Our life was pleasant enough,
although dangerous.
But then the six
King's Spears came, right?
Yes.
When a skilled spear-wielder...
...with a young woman in tow
takes on bodyguard jobs...
...word is going to get around
whether you want it to or not.
On the way home after a big job...
...we were finally
discovered by the King's Spears...
...who had been tracking
our activities all that time.
Go hide in those rocks over there.
Go!
I was reluctant to leave him.
I had believed that I would be
able to help Jiguro, at least a little...
...but when the time came
to face the King's Spears...
...I wasn't able to do anything.
No, even if I had
been able to help...
...I'm certain that Jiguro
wouldn't have let me.
Stop! This will accomplish nothing!
Jiguro had already
made up his mind.
He would fight the
King's Spears alone.
Listen to me! Put away
your spears and return to Kanball
How long do you intend to
continue such a futile endeavor?
Jiguro had decided that
he wouldn't allow my hands...
...to be stained
by senseless killing.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
From Jiguro to Balsa.
From Balsa to Chagum.
Inherited desires. Tested bonds.
Next time, "Season of Awakening."
Episode 22
Season of Awakening
Spring is almost upon us.