I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
Stop! This will accomplish nothing!
Listen to me! Put away
your spears and return to Kanball
How long do you intend to
continue such a futile endeavor?
Episode 22
Season of Awakening
Stay back!
At that point, it had nothing to do
with the King's Spears or anything else.
It was just a battle to the death.
And that was how Jiguro
killed all of the King's Spears...
...who had been
sent to hunt us down.
He did it to protect
both me and himself.
But in the process, his own soul was
lost along with those eight people's.
Along with the eight people's?
Right. The souls I talked about the
night I took you under my protection...
...were those of the
King's Spears that Jiguro killed.
Because of Logsam, Jiguro and I
were forced to walk a cruel path in life.
Even so, those dead men didn't
deserve to be killed over nothing either.
So you see, my life has been
built on their sacrifice.
Care to eat dinner?
That's why you swore to...
...save the same number of
people that Jiguro killed, isn't it?
Yes. Jiguro told me to
forget about it, though.
But if it weren't for that vow,
I would be dead.
I suppose you would.
Anyway, that was
my reason for doing it.
But aside from the fact
that my father was his friend...
...Jiguro had no reason to save me.
Why was Jiguro willing to kill
eight of his friends to save you?
I don't know. That question
has always bothered me.
Why did he agree to
my father's request?
Why didn't he abandon me
somewhere along the way?
Why did he agree to something
that would gain him nothing...
...and would cost him everything
that he had worked for?
I want to find out why he did.
If I could understand
what Jiguro was thinking...
...maybe I could accept my
own situation a little better.
Care to continue the discussion
over dinner downstairs?
I feel like reminiscing
about Jiguro too.
After the fight with the King's Spears
was over, what did you do, Balsa?
My training with Jiguro
was complete by that point...
...so my skills were more than a
match for any of the local warriors.
Plus, I was 16 by then...
...so I understood
Jiguro's suffering all too well.
That's why I said to him...
"Let's go our separate ways."
Jiguro, let's split up.
I can take care of myself now.
So please...
You've already saved
me so many times.
So please, forget about me.
Focus on your own
happiness from now on.
You may feel as if you
owe me an enormous debt...
...but don't think of
the past that way.
It'll only leave you
with an empty feeling.
Besides, Balsa...
I've grown fond of
both you and our life here.
When Jiguro said that,
I was at a loss for words.
But in spite of what he said...
...he had tried his utmost
to avoid fighting his friends.
And even though he said
he was fond of me...
...that certainly wasn't
the case at first.
After all, women may have...
...maternal instincts, but they aren't
something men are born with.
In the end, I never learned
what Jiguro was thinking...
...when he first escaped with me.
Some five years
after that, Jiguro died.
He wasn't defeated by pursuers.
He succumbed to an illness.
By that time,
King Logsam was dead...
...so there was no reason
for us to keep living like fugitives.
Fifteen years had passed
since the two of us first left Kanbal.
I give you my word.
I'll save eight souls.
I'll lay your friends'
souls to rest. I promise.
So please...rest easy.
Balsa...
it's much harder to save lives
than it is to take them...
Are you trying to become
a hero or something?
People often yearn for a hero
who will sacrifice his life for them.
Saving lives isn't something
that you do on a whim.
Stop trying so hard.
But you know, Chagum,
this is how I see it now.
Maybe Jiguro was someone who
thought if you're in a position to act...
...it would be a sin not to, even if you
had nothing to gain from doing so.
To Jiguro, being a national hero and
protecting some nameless person...
...they were the same thing.
He even hoped to spare the
lives of his pursuers if he could.
I finally understand that now.
After becoming your bodyguard.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
We can't talk you out of going?
There's no time like the present.
Besides, winter will be at its
harshest over the next two months.
If I don't leave now, the snow
will have me good and stuck here.
I have better things to do than spend
the whole winter cooped up in here!
Surely you don't need to
go to the health springs...
...at an important time like this!
Relax, I'll be back
before the spring thaw.
Mistress Torogai,
are you going somewhere?
To the hot springs, boy!
The hot springs!
Oh.
Chagum, why are
you carrying that?
Teach me how to fight too.
I want to learn as much as I can
to protect the egg and myself.
If I'm stronger, I might be able to
get away even if Rarunga attacks...
...and I might be able to make sure
the egg hatches safely even if I die.
After all, I'm the
guardian of the spirit.
You're right.
But I'm not going to let you die.
I'll protect you no matter what.
Huh? Teacher...
Yes, what?
I thought it was unusual, that's all.
So, you can make
that expression too?
No one cares what you think!
I'm going!
Balsa, feel free to train the boy
if you want, but don't go overboard.
Unlike you, he doesn't seem to
have any talent for the martial arts.
Hey, that's mean!
Hmph, I'm just stating the facts.
Well, I'm off.
Caw, caw, hey, hey!
Will tomorrow bring fair
weather, a blizzard, or rain?
Look, the Misty Blues
are slightly cloudy.
Don't let the paddies dry out.
Call for water!
Nurture the seedlings
and spread the fertilizer!
Nahji, fly, fly! Nahji, fly, fly!
If you fly to the sea,
the rice plants will grow swiftly.
What's up, why are you
standing there in the doorway?
Huh? Oh.
I was just thinking that
this really takes me back.
Jiguro sometimes watched
over you as you slept...
...after the day's training was over,
just like you are now.
Balsa, this winter has
been a good one, hasn't it?
With the three of us
together like this...
...I hoped that this winter
would go on forever.
But spring will be here soon.
These quiet days are almost over.
Rarunga will probably
be waking soon too.
Probably. We'll be facing
a life-or-death struggle soon.
Balsa, if we all make it
through this battle alive...
...how about the three of us
living together like we did this winter?
I've always been
hesitant to bring it up.
I thought I should wait until
after you'd fulfilled your promise.
But even if I did wait,
you'd never notice it.
Battles are your whole
life now, aren't they?
I'm not sure how I can cure that...
Do you have any medicine for it?
If you can't think of me as the cure,
I guess there's no point in me waiting.
You idiot...
Don't you think I have
enough on my mind right now?
Chagum!
What's the matter? Chagum!
Chagum, what in the
world happened?
This is...
There's no ground...
I'm floating above a deep valley.
Balsa!
I'm falling! I'm falling!
Don't let Chagum drag you across!
He's being pulled into Nayug!
What should I do!
You've got to be the anchor
that keeps Chagum fixed in place!
I'm falling!
Calm down, Chagum.
The valley that you're seeing
doesn't exist here in this place.
What you're seeing is
the landscape of Nayug.
Can you hear me?
Your body is still right here in Sag...
You're going to be fine.
You aren't going to fall.
Chagum, I want you
to calm yourself...
...and focus on
Balsa's arms around you.
Well? Do you feel them now?
Use Balsa's body as your guide.
Moving outwards from where she's
touching you, sense your own body.
Slowly bring your mind
back to this side.
Remember what it looks like here.
You're at Hunter's Hole,
the place you've been living all winter.
Can you see me, Chagum?
I can see you...
Chagum!
It's all right. His soul has
returned to this world. Don't worry.
Do you think this happened
because of the egg?
Well, it is almost spring...
I guess this means
it's finally started.
How is the work progressing,
Master Gakai?
I'm amazed. To think that so many
epitaphs were hidden beneath our feet...
I cannot help but feel regret
at all the time we have wasted.
How are preparations
going on your end?
I was finally able to determine
the approximate location...
...of the land of feasting
the other day.
I see.
However, recovering
the very last of the tablets...
...from the lowest, flooded levels
is taking much time and effort.
What's more, many of
them contain information...
...that is crucial to
our understanding.
Though I would prefer to obtain all
available information as soon as possible...
...I ask that you rest a while.
Perhaps you should direct
those words at yourself.
You have dark circles
under your eyes.
Now that we have learned the
secret behind the country's founding...
...we cannot afford to
have you collapse on us.
Leave this to us. Mark my
words. We will finish in time.
Master Gakai.
I'll be right there.
If we turn up anything,
we will notify you at once.
Master Shuga, the
mikado wishes to see you.
When did we last have snow?
It was about the time of the first
month of the new year, as I recall.
Who would ever have
imagined that clear blue skies...
...would instill such dread and
fill my heart with such worry?
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
The egg awakens
with the spring thaw...
...and the being from another world
also reaches its time of emergence.
Next time,
"In Search of the Shigu Salua."
Episode 23
In Search of the Shigu Salua
The scent of flowers draws everyone
to the last place they can be found.