I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
There wasn't much snow this winter.
Ah, I see.
Nyunga Ro Im died, did he?
Episode 23
In Search of the Shigu Salua
I'm sorry. We weren't able to decipher
everything before your departure.
Not at all. It's enough
that we found a way...
...to protect the prince
from the egg-eater.
That is true.
Even a demon from Nayug...
...can be defeated
if struck at its weak point.
Thank you very much.
If we uncover anything new,
I shall dispatch a rider to you.
You should go.
So, the time has finally
come for you to set off.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I shall save Prince Chagum's life...
...even if the price
should be my own.
Good luck to you.
However, you must
return safely to us as well.
You have already become
indispensable to this country.
I will take my leave.
What's the matter, Chagum?
Torogai!
Torogai? You're riding
that donkey again?
Well, it insisted on coming with me.
Boy?
You're starting to
look like a man, I see.
Well, Chagum is 12 now, after all.
I had a feeling that
this might happen.
Here.
What's this?
You can't walk around in
children's clothes forever.
Change into those,
and let's have a look at you!
Come to think of it, Tanda...
...also had a growth spurt
around that age, didn't he?
I did?
You sure did. Till then, you
were just my cute little brother.
That's when it occurred to me.
The passage of time
changes all sorts of things.
Shoo.
Thanks for your help.
Here, catch. That's what
you asked me to get for you.
You weren't a prince
for nothing, I see.
Do I look strange?
It looks good on you.
You look like a fine young man now.
This is from me.
A sword's weight is a life's weight.
The sword you hold represents
your life as well as your death.
Whenever you draw it...
...do so in the knowledge that you
have entrusted your life to its blade.
It's a saying we have in Kanbal.
It's recited during the
coming-of-age ritual...
...when a son receives
his first short sword.
Of course, the father
is supposed to say it.
Thank you, Balsa.
Chagum, what's the matter?
I was summoned.
By whom?
It's not a voice.
It's a powerful sensation like I'm being
pulled by a string that I can't see.
The egg was
whispering to you, I see.
So, where do you want to go?
Well, well...
So, the land of feasting
is one of the springs...
...that feed into the Aoyumi
like it said in the official history?
All right, boy,
show us the way there.
Let's move out.
Look at that motherly
expression on your face.
Is that wrong?
Assuming that you survive all this...
...what do you plan
to do afterwards?
There's something to be said
for settling down in one place.
Having children and raising
them is enjoyable enough.
You make it sound like
you've had children of your own.
I've had three of them.
What, really?
Why would I lie about
something like that?
Lately...
Lately, I've had
this recurring dream.
A dream?
Yes.
What sort of dream?
Ah, I see...
Say, Tanda...
Did you ever get an
answer from Balsa?
Answer to what?
You know, what you said
to her back at Hunter's Hole.
About the three of us
living together.
You were listening?
I don't know what to say...
You should just marry her
as soon as you can.
Don't make it sound so easy.
Balsa and I both
have complicated lives.
Are you talking
about Balsa's oath?
Well, there's that, but we've
probably spent too much time together.
It's like we've gradually
grown farther apart or something.
In the old days, my feelings for her
were hot like the summer sunshine.
Over the years, though...
...they've changed...
turned warm like the autumn wind.
Anyway, that's why I'm fine with
keeping things the way they are.
Are you sure?
Look, let's just forget
about this, please.
No matter how much I mull over it,
this is one thing I can't solve on my own.
Then why don't I go
ask Balsa for you?
When did you get
so decisive, Chagum?
And here I am, scared out of
my wits over just about everything.
I realized something.
Even if I die, I know I'll be able to
leave behind a legacy, so it's all right.
Ever since Balsa
told me all about Jiguro...
...I've been able to
look at life that way.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
We're not to engage the
spear-wielder? I don't follow you, sir.
Our interests coincide with hers.
There is no longer
any reason to fight her.
In addition, there are Prince
Chagum's feelings to consider.
Understood.
Master Shuga.
As per your instructions,
three of our best archers...
...have been concealed
on the return trail.
I see.
But are you sure that's
what you want to do?
We have no choice.
It is what the mikado ordered.
There isn't much water.
Looks like the first signs of drought
are starting to show themselves.
So, up ahead is the
promised land, eh?
Look at all those shigu salua flowers.
Aoike? This is
the land of feasting?
I don't know.
Mistress Torogai, we have come
to fulfil our end of the bargain.
Well, I'm glad to see that
you didn't come empty-handed!
Crown Prince Chagum.
We have come to assist
in the birth of the water spirit...
...and to welcome you back as
the hero who saved Shin-Yogo.
Shuga, so my brother is truly...
So, he's "the hero who
saved Yogo" now, is he?
That's quite a change
of heart you've had.
Female bodyguard,
our interests now coincide.
I realize that we may not
have always seen eye to eye...
...but these men no longer
mean you any harm.
Star reader. Your words may sound noble,
but if we now share a common goal...
...cut to the chase and
tell us how to kill the Rarunga.
A Rarunga's weakness is fire.
It was written in the epitaphs
that the Warriors Eight...
...who served the founding father
drove off the Rarunga using fire.
Now I see! it's a question of
relative strengths between spirits.
Water is beaten by earth,
and earth is beaten by fire.
Rarunga, which devour the egg of the
water spirit...are they earth spirits?
Damn, I can't believe I didn't
make such a simple connection...
Then the torches used in the summer
solstice festival are vestiges of that?
That's right.
And now, 200 years later,
that duty has once again fallen to us.
So, you are the descendants
of the Warriors Eight.
Chagum?
Chagum!
Incredible!
The power of the egg?
Wait! Don't do anything rash.
Torogai, it was written
that the egg is to be born...
...on the night of the spring equinox
when the double moon rises.
Nightfall is still far off.
What, then, is causing...
No idea. I don't know
what's going to happen either.
You'd best be on
your guard, though.
Chagum...
What in the world is he doing?
We were wrong...
We were mistaken, Shuga!
How can this be?
Why did we learn this only now?
How many tablets are left!
There should be eight remaining.
Bring them all up in one go!
Go summon the retrieval team!
But, master, we can't make them
dive so many times in a single day.
Where does your duty lie?
Will you read the stars
in a destroyed nation?
Prince Sagum,
grant me your protection...
Chagum, are you all right?
This sense of malice...
it's not natural.
Is it something from Nayug?
But where is it?
That's...
Is that a Rarunga?
Is that the egg-eater?
Light your weapons!
Take position!
You people stay back!
My senses, they're...
Chagum!
Attack!
Is it dead?
It's still here!
Chagum?
Chagum!
Highness!
Where does that boy
think he's going?
Master Gakai!
Shuga, Aoike isn't
the land of feasting...
Master Gakai!
S-Send these tablets
to Shuga at Aoike!
He should be able to
decipher them on the spot...
If the messenger rides at top speed,
he'll make it in time!
Master Gakai...
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
They have finally made
peace with each other.
However, the missing epitaphs
turn everything on its head.
Next time, "The Last Hope."
Episode 24
The Last Hope
Tanda's courage
keeps their hopes alive.