I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
It's still here!
Chagum?
Chagum!
Episode 24
The Last Hope
What happened to Chagum?
Balsa!
I'm coming with you!
Come on then!
Calm yourselves!
Remain calm!
Regroup into your teams!
Squads one and two,
accompany me in pursuit of the prince...
Hold on there.
Don't be so hasty!
If this place is the land of feasting,
the boy will come back eventually.
After all, the egg is supposed
to hatch at dawn tomorrow.
Perhaps, but...
Leave the pursuit to that bunch.
You'll never be able
to catch up with them.
What the two of us ought to be
doing is exchanging information.
Am I right?
Yes...yes, of course.
Perhaps you're right.
Men! Set up bonfires
along the pond's periphery!
We mustn't allow the Rarunga to
attack again when the prince returns!
Make your preparations at once!
Yes, sir!
Mistress Torogai, the epitaphs
hidden beneath the palace...
...say much the same thing
that you told us in Toumi village.
It says the guardian of the spirit
will be ripped apart by the egg-eater.
However, we had
the good fortune...
...to learn that Rarunga
could be kept at bay with fire.
Could you tell me
exactly what it said?
On this day 200 years ago,
our founding father used fire...
...to rescue a Yakoo child
named Sigul from the Rarunga.
However, the egg exists
between Nayug and Sagu...
...not within the child itself.
Apparently, the Nyunga Ro Chaga has
no means to deliver the egg himself.
As I thought, the only way for the egg
to come out is if it's eaten by a Rarunga?
Master Star Reader
Nanai seems to...
...have observed the
events in minute detail.
He and a Yakooan magic weaver
who had accompanied them...
...tried desperately
to extract the egg.
And then, just when their spell
was on the verge of success...
...the child was torn
apart by a Rarunga...
...which had come
once again from Nayug.
What became of
the egg after that?
Moments after the Rarunga tore
the child apart and swallowed it...
...they witnessed an orb glowing
with a blue light shoot from its mouth.
After that, something called
a "nahjil" carried it away.
However, this term "nahjil"
does not exist in our language.
Do you have any idea
what this nahjil might be?
Yes.
It means a nahji, I expect.
The birds in the
Yakoo rice-planting song.
Oh, I see...
Damn it all...
I had hoped that the answers you
brought would answer everything...
...but they've left us with more
difficult problems than ever.
Then you do not know any spells
to extract the egg, either?
No. I won't have any idea what
I might try until it actually happens.
And even assuming that
I manage to extract the egg...
...who's to say that
a nahji will come to us?
That's true...
This isn't good...
Damn. I can't even
find any footprints.
It's possible that Chagum
is moving from tree to tree.
Tree to tree?
Right. You saw him
do it too, didn't you?
Chagum ran on top of the water.
The egg intends to lead the Rarunga
on a chase until dawn to protect itself.
That's probably also the reason why
Chagum ate that shigu salua flower.
The scent of flowers
attracts creatures of Nayug.
Also...
You lost sight of the prince too?
Meaning that you didn't
have any luck, either?
No.
We chased after the Rarunga,
but it suddenly disappeared.
And as you said, Prince Chagum
fled by leaping from tree to tree.
He moved so quickly that not
even we could keep up with him.
You there. Where do you
believe the prince is headed?
I don't know for sure, but if Aoike
really is the land of feasting...
...he might return
by daybreak.
At any rate, Chagum is under
the control of the egg right now.
Wandering around the forest
isn't going to accomplish anything.
Commander, should we return
to Aoike for the time being?
We mustn't! Even if His Highness
really is being controlled by the egg...
...what if he is
attacked by a Rarunga?
I'm also against returning to Aoike.
If that's the land of feasting...
...and he's running from the Rarunga
until sunrise, why would he do that?
He deliberately fled into the forest.
Don't you think there's a reason?
Indeed. I agree with
what the spear-wielder says.
According to Master
Shuga's deductions...
...the Rarunga would
not attack until dawn.
There must have been
some sort of miscalculation.
In which case, our only option
is to locate Chagum ourselves.
So it would seem.
Where do you intend to go?
You're going to follow that
riverbed farther upstream?
The Rarunga will come again...
it's a good thing that we
don't have to fight those people.
It's clear even to me
just how skilled they are.
You think so?
Spear-wielder.
There's one question I had been
meaning to ask if we ever met again.
That first time we crossed swords,
our team of four failed to kill you.
I do not believe we were overly
confident in our superior numbers.
Why didn't you kill us that night?
I believe you could have killed
all of us had you wished to.
No reason in particular.
I had just agreed to save someone, so
I thought it would defeat the purpose...
...if I killed someone
else in the process.
I see.
If it had been because
you were looking down on us...
...I had planned to settle the matter
here and now to redeem our honor.
But it would seem we
were outmatched all along.
Soon, when we find ourselves
in a cataclysmic battle...
...we will follow you
without hesitation.
Stop that. You're embarrassing me.
My magic allows me to
see the egg inside the boy.
However, I've never
been able to touch it.
Even so, if we can find some other
way to interact with Nayug, maybe I...
What was that?
What's that commotion?
Master Shuga!
Is Master Shuga here?
Master Shuga, I have a
message from Master Gakai.
Aoike is not the land of feasting!
Saanan, the land of feasting,
is located somewhere else entirely!
What? What do you mean?
He says that Saanan's precise
location is recorded on these tablets.
If this isn't the land of feasting,
we're in trouble...
Indeed.
I'd say that it's about
three bells before dawn.
I can't believe it. How could we have
missed something so important?
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Incredible!
Written here is a scene that is identical
to what we witnessed not long ago.
Two hundred years ago,
another child ate a flower...
...and disappeared into the forest,
leading the Rarunga after him.
Also, it would seem that in Nayug,
this location is the Rarunga's lair.
The child ate the flower to get
the Rarunga to follow it, then?
Yes.
Also, it says that Saanan is some
twenty nan to the north of here.
Twenty nan? We'll be lucky to
cover that distance by daybreak.
I will gather my forces,
and we will leave at once.
Right, but first we should tell those
who went on ahead about this.
But we--
Calm down.
Luck is still on our side, since
that nitwit Tanda wouldn't leave her.
If this pond is a location that overlaps
with Nayug, this ought to work.
Commander.
Seems to be no doubt about it.
No, sir.
They lead up that riverbed.
If he's come back
down to the ground...
...he might be planning to
attract the egg-eater again.
Let's try following the river.
Right.
All right, it worked...
Now we have to pray
that Tanda spots it.
If those young pups of yours
have joined forces with Balsa...
...they'll probably turn up too.
They'll be a lot more
useful than this bunch here.
It'll be a lucky break for us if
they reach Saanan before we do.
You know how to ride a horse?
We'll ride on ahead on that.
Tell your troops to follow after us.
We can't let that
egg hatch without us!
Right!
Who said that?
Hey, Balsa!
Come look at this!
Did he find something?
Let's go check it out.
What's the matter?
Did you find something?
Someone is calling me.
...Tanda...
Y-Yes, that's right.
My name is Tanda.
...Torogai...
...Chagum...
The land of feasting is
twenty nan to the north.
Chagum is headed there too.
Is that all?
What in the world are you doing?
I just got a message
from the mistress.
I know where Chagum is headed.
Chagum is headed for
a place called Saanan...
...one of the Aoyumi's headwaters.
Apparently, that's the
real land of feasting.
Your hunch was right, Balsa.
Which means we have
to reach it before dawn!
It's less than three bells to sunrise!
They're following
on our heels, right?
Yes. They are an elite,
handpicked force.
I am certain that they
will catch up with us.
If we get there,
and it's just us two...
Certainly not an ideal scenario...
...but if that should be the case,
I shall protect the prince myself!
Look at this.
Yes, it's Chagum's.
It hasn't been long since
he passed through here.
Out of the way!
It's those two
creatures from before.
Are they looking for the prince?
Looks that way.
They're much more visible than
they were this afternoon, though.
Did they catch his scent?
We can see them...
why can't we hit them?
Damn!
It's no use! It won't work unless the
Rarunga is trying to interact with Sagu!
Tanda!
What did you do?
How could you touch it?
These.
When the Rarunga
appeared at Aoike...
...the only things it affected were the
roots and blossoms of these flowers.
I thought I should bring
some along just in case.
Looks like it was the right call.
If we eat these like Chagum did,
we'll be able to touch the Rarunga too.
The downside is that we'll also be
at risk of being killed by those things.
You're hurt!
Balsa, these flowers
are our last hope.
Can you use these
to save Chagum?
Yes.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
After the passage of a hundred
years, the promised day dawns.
Saanan is a place of celebration
where living things go to kindle new life.
Next time, "Celebration."
Episode 25
Celebration
Father, child, and mother
will celebrate together there.