I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
The river source should be close.
Am I halfway between
Nayug and Sagu?
Episode 25
Celebration
Balsa, these flowers
are our last hope.
Can you use these
to save Chagum?
All right. I'll give it a try.
I'll do whatever it takes
to protect Chagum.
Herbologist, will those
flowers work for us as well?
Yes. If I cast a
quick spell on them...
...they should allow
anyone to see Nayug.
Give each of us one
of those flowers too.
We will take up your cause even if...
...we ourselves are
torn apart in the process. Please!
I see. Thank you. I was
planning to ask for your help anyway.
All of you, please protect Chagum.
Many thanks!
We should simply eat them as is?
Yes.
All right, everyone, let's go!
To Nayug, where
Chagum has gone!
Which way?
That way!
There's no sign of that
other egg-eater from before.
It's no use. I can't see anything.
Does the shigu salua
have no effect on me?
It's possible that they
don't take effect immediately.
Have faith in the
herbologist's magic.
For now, our top priority is
catching up to Prince Chagum.
What sort of instructions have
you been given by that star reader?
Master Shuga has told us
that if the need should arise...
...to forget about the egg and
focus on protecting the prince.
I see. In a sense, that
might be the right decision.
For now, let's gamble
on that decision.
Even if the egg is born, it's meaningless
if Chagum is killed in the process.
Looks like the bleeding
has stopped.
It's a living creature, all right.
I can't imagine something
like this coming from our world.
What in the world is that!
Did you get my message?
Yes. Balsa and those warriors
went ahead to Saanan.
I see.
I expected no less from one who
receives Mistress Torogai's teachings.
More importantly...
More importantly, what
happened to this monster?
How did you defeat it?
I tried eating a shigu salua flower.
I discovered that the flower's
pollen acts as a medium...
...and that allows us humans
to interact with Nayug.
Ah, I see...
Well done, pupil of mine!
So, do you have any
more of those flowers?
I'm sorry. But I gave all of them
to Balsa and the others.
Damn...
Young as you are, you might live
to see another rebirth of the spirit...
...but this was my last chance.
Come on, this was
my last chance too.
Mistress Torogai,
we should make haste as well.
Right now, protecting the prince is...
Don't be in such a hurry.
He won't be eaten until dawn.
Mistress, that bear...
I see it. It's also carrying a...
A Rarunga?
You can see it?
Yes.
Was that a...
Yes, it was probably
a Nyunga Ro Im egg.
I suspected that there might
be others besides Chagum.
Being culled like that is probably
part of the natural order.
Then, Chagum might also...
Right, he might not be safe
until daybreak after all.
We need to hurry, star reader!
Mistress, take me with you!
Yes, we should take him too.
Oh, all right.
You get on the horse, then!
It's strange. I'm not cold at all...
So this is Saanan...
Are you ready to be born, then?
Balsa!
Balsa...
But I...
Chagum! Stay where you are!
Balsa...
Your Highness!
Spear-wielder, you go on ahead!
Right! Do what you
can to hold it off!
Chagum!
Balsa!
You're all right!
Balsa, I knew you
would come for me.
I always had faith in you, Balsa.
Sune! Shoot this!
Did I get it?
That's a...
In Nayug, this area is under water.
Teacher, this area appears
to be underwater in Nayug.
Let's find a way up to
the top of those cliffs.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Have we done it?
Balsa! Chagum!
You can see the prince?
Where is he?
Damn, I can't see them, either.
To think my student can
see something that I can't...
How can this be?
The world I know, the world I see...
is it no more than half of this world?
No, one ten-thousandth?
Anyway, let's hurry.
No! You mustn't kill the Rarunga!
What's the matter, Chagum?
You want to come out?
You can't come out unless
I'm torn apart by the Rarunga?
I hate this... This is something that
I can't do anything to help with.
Mistress, I'll go on ahead!
There are more?
Commander, I'm
almost out of arrows.
We don't have much oil left, either.
The Warriors Eight of legend...
...fought on in this situation
for three days and nights.
We may run out of oil,
but thanks to the herbalist...
...we can now confront
these Nayug creatures in battle.
Even if all we have left are our swords,
we shall fight to the death!
The commander is right!
We can do this!
Spear-wielder, take the prince and
flee from here while we hold them off!
His escape is our top priority!
Understood. Chagum, hang on.
We're getting away from here.
I can't... I can't leave, Balsa.
The egg wants to stay here.
If it isn't born here today,
it's going to die inside of me.
I can't let that happen!
The egg wants to be born here!
Go, Spear-wielder! Hurry!
Sune!
Balsa, I still want to live too.
But I'm going to put
myself in fate's hands.
I can't live if it means
sacrificing your lives...
...or sacrificing
Yogo's million citizens.
So please, stop fighting!
I'll do what has to be done!
Chagum...
Your Highness!
Your Highness, don't concern
yourselves about us. Just run!
Everyone...
Tanda!
It looks like he's
crossed over into Nayug.
Balsa!
Don't worry, Chagum!
I can extract the egg using
a spell I learned from Torogai.
We need to get Chagum
to someplace safe first.
You mean it?
...200 years ago who made the
same attempt and nearly succeeded.
I'll take your word for it.
Keep an eye on Chagum for me!
It's all right. There's nothing
to worry about, Chagum!
Torogai, is there
nothing that we can do?
Nothing. Just sit quietly
and pray for the sun to rise.
Please, Chagum,
you have to move!
How many of these
things are there?
There's no end to them!
Torogai?
They seem to be fighting
a huge number of Rarunga.
Damn!
I suppose I'll go too...
Everyone, follow the
spear-wielder's lead!
Balsa!
The morning sun?
I get it. The sun must
have come up in Sag...
We made it?
Your Highness?
Balsa...
Hurry!
Torogai!
If we don't hurry, Nayug and
Sagu will separate completely.
Right.
Balsa, give me a hand.
Listen...
Gently reach inside.
It hurts!
It's all right.
Gently take hold of the egg.
It hurts!
Well? Did you find it?
That is the egg?
You were safely born, weren't you?
Your wish to live came true.
You've done it, Tanda, Balsa.
Yes.
Balsa, let me see the egg too.
You were very brave...
it's warm.
Now, the next order of business...
Yes, the nahji.
Yes. If no nahji come, that
unprotected egg will probably die soon.
Nahji!
Nahji have come!
You're right! it's nahji!
They're flying off without seeing us.
It's all right. They'll see us.
It's coming back!
Chagum, what should we do now?
Throw the egg high into the sky,
and the nahji will take it in its beak.
Now they show up...
Indeed... But now we can
give him a return worthy of a king.
It's all over. My fight
against destiny is finally over...
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.
Next Time
Chagum and Balsa have
entrusted the egg to the nahji.
What fate awaits them
now that it is all over?
The final episode, "Departure."
Episode 26
Departure
I will never forget you.