I want to shine on you,
and always like that dazzling sun.
I will defend you
from all the darkness.
This is the truth from my heart.
If only our hearts could connect,
I could get you to believe me.
Even if you can't
see it now, don't lose it.
Your kindness won't be in vain.
You'll be carried aloft by the wind
to somewhere that isn't here.
You'll cross the sea and cross time,
and I know you'll blossom one day.
Whatever the day,
I'll be there for you.
I hope I can watch over you
like the sun for all time.
This is the truth from my heart.
I bring news!
Well done.
Good news, I trust?
Yes.
His Highness Prince Chagum
has driven off the evil demons...
...rendered assistance in
the birth of the water spirit...
...and is returning to the
palace at this very moment.
He has done well...
I shall immediately lift the order of
silence and have the entire palace...
...begin preparations
for a ceremony.
Let it be known far and wide.
He is the founding father Torugaru
reborn, who, by the grace of heaven...
...paved the way for the
creation of our country.
Yes, Sire.
Episode 26
Departure
Say, Balsa...
Do you think the nahji has carried
the egg all the way to the sea by now?
I wonder when it will
become a water spirit?
I'm not sure.
But if it doesn't start
belching out some clouds soon...
...the harvest this fall
is going to be poor.
You're right.
Come to think of it, Teacher, what
do you suppose Rarunga normally eat?
I doubt that they go 100 years
without eating anything.
Of course not. Even those
monsters are living things.
I expect that they eat other
creatures the rest of the time...
...and the Nyunga Ro Chaga are
a treat they only get once a century.
Now I see. Even though
they're called egg-eaters...
...they can't actually eat the eggs.
Was there anyone besides me
that was implanted with an egg?
Actually, there was a bear cub.
We saw it get eaten by a Rarunga.
Oh.
What would you like us to do, sir?
The prince seldom leaves
the spear-wielder's side.
Forgive me, female bodyguard.
Wait!
Master Shuga, even if you were
so ordered by the mikado...
...surely it is no longer necessary.
None of us wish to cause
His Highness more grief.
You should feel that desire
more keenly than anyone.
Yes, you are right. I was
about to do the wrong thing.
I shall discuss this with the mikado.
Mon, Jin, thank you.
You have my gratitude.
Chagum, go ride in the palanquin.
They look embarrassed.
I can't do that.
It wouldn't feel right to ride in the
palanquin when you're hurt, Tanda.
I appreciate the sentiment, but...
Oh, let him have his way.
Chagum says he doesn't mind.
Right. And besides,
we're almost at Kosenkyo.
Balsa...
Why don't you start off by letting
your mother see that you're safe?
I have made arrangements
for you within the palace as well.
Please relax and enjoy
yourselves until you are sent for.
I like the sound of that. Why don't
we have ourselves a grand time?
We will look after your spear.
Chagum...
Mother!
Chagum!
Chagum...I always believed.
I always believed that you were
still alive somewhere out there...
Look at how you have grown.
Yes, thanks to Balsa.
Yes, what became of that woman?
She came back with me.
She is probably somewhere
with Shuga in the palace.
I see.
Prince Sagum, thank you.
This bath hits the spot...
Doesn't it?
What's the matter?
You look awfully pensive over there.
It's nothing. It's finally starting
to hit home that it's really over.
What do you plan to do now?
I don't know. I still have no idea.
Set out on another journey?
I haven't given that
any thought either.
Actually, there's talk of
arranging a bride for Tanda.
When I went to the health
springs over the winter...
...an old acquaintance of mine
kept pestering me about it.
She says her daughter...
...saw Tanda brewing medicine
for a retired old geezer there...
...and fell head over heels for him.
Like me, she's quite a looker.
She has a fine disposition too.
They sound like a fine match.
For heaven's sake...
I can't possibly eat all this food.
I suppose I'll start with the food
that looks like it will go bad first.
Are you an idiot?
Don't be so stingy. Start with
whatever you want to eat!
Teacher, don't you think
you've had too much to drink?
Who asked you?
I plan to drink every last drop
of liquor they have in the palace!
Hey! Bring me more sake!
Honestly...
Still, it's no wonder that a simple
bowl of porridge seemed new to him...
...if he was served
feasts like this every day.
Right, Balsa?
I suppose so.
Don't worry!
We'll see Chagum soon.
That couldn't possibly have been
the last time we'd ever see him.
Besides, I'm sure that Chagum
is just as eager to see you.
I guess you're right.
Look at me.
Moribito Guardian of the Spirit
Approach me.
No, closer.
It is good that you have returned.
Thank you.
Shuga has informed me of
what transpired on your journey.
It must have been long and difficult.
Nevertheless, it was one
worthy of a child of heaven.
Truly a great deed.
It was only through the assistance of
a great many people that I succeeded.
Especially that of Balsa, who--
Forget you ever met that woman!
To the common masses...
...you are the hero who saved
the country in her time of crisis.
For a country, as well as for
all those who reside in it...
...having a hero is the
greatest possible honor.
One which no amount
of money can buy!
You are a treasure
bestowed upon us by heaven!
I am given to understand that this Kanbal
woman is a most capable individual...
...one who protected you with no
thought of reward or her own safety.
Surely she would have no
objections to you being our hero...
...and guiding the
Shin-Yogo empire into the future.
Chagum...
Live as our hero.
With Sagum now gone,
your role is now to live as a hero.
For both you, who has made
an ally of the water spirit...
...as well as for Shin-Yogo,
the road ahead is a bright one!
Shuga, what is Balsa doing?
She is resting in the
guest quarters, Your Highness.
I see...
Please understand,
Your Highness.
The moment you returned here,
you became the crown prince.
Arrangements have been
made for them to receive...
...a more than suitable reward
before the ceremony tomorrow.
Balsa must have known
that this would happen.
That is why she
told me about Jiguro.
How long are these people
going to keep us waiting?
Balsa, is that...
Yeah.
They weren't kidding when they
said that the clothes make the man.
Teacher!
Relax, they can't hear me.
In light of your service to His Highness
the crown prince, child of heaven...
...His Majesty the mikado
shall now reward you!
You there, step forward.
Next.
Balsa, thank you.
It's too much trouble!
Go up there and fetch mine.
I'd rather talk to Chagum one more
time than receive something like this.
In that case, I'll take your
share off your hands later.
You and your jokes...
Halt! Commoners are not allowed
to pass through this gate.
Go down the path to the right.
What's the meaning of this?
That path is more suitable
for the likes of you.
Hey, I think you're
taking this a little too far.
Go.
I suppose we should
do as they say for now.
Chagum!
Balsa!
L...I don't want to be
the crown prince!
I want to keep traveling
with you forever!
I don't want to leave you, Balsa!
Chagum, do you want
to run away with me?
Well? Would you like me
to cause a commotion?
You don't have to cause a commotion.
You can save it for some other child.
And maybe that child
will be yours and Tanda's!
That's a good one! Well said!
You've learned to
speak your mind, I see!
I'm going back now.
Right.
Balsa.
I want you to call me Chagum.
I want you to say,
"Goodbye, Chagum."
Sure. Goodbye, Chagum.
Thank you, Balsa.
Tanda, Torogai, goodbye.
Looks like Torogai will be
staying at the hut for a while.
She is, is she?
I wish I could've talked
to Chagum again too.
Who's to say that you
won't see him again?
I guess, but...
Still, I wonder why Balsa decided
to go back to Kanbal all of a sudden?
Hey, that's right!
I thought that Chagum was
supposed to be her eighth soul.
She said she was going to
settle down after that.
There's one other person
that only Balsa can put to rest.
Well, I just hope she doesn't keep you
waiting another two years this time.
If she does, I'll deal with it.
I'll still be here.
I swear, there's such a
thing as too much patience...
Tanda?
What's the matter, Tanda?
A cloud!
I should have had some of Tanda's
wild vegetable stew before I left.
As I sat huddled and alone, holding
back the tears on those nights...
When it felt like I was about
to succumb to my doubts...
...there you were,
at my side before I knew it.
It was none other than you
who was there for me.
I keep wishing, "I want to be strong."
I stumble and hurt myself again.
But because I have you to believe in,
I can get back to my feet.
I simply want to tell
my dear one, "Thank you. "
At the top of my lungs,
again and again.
I call out to my precious loved one.
Is my voice reaching you?
In this world that always changes,
human warmth never does.
I'm certain I sensed the presence
of the one that I hold dear.